So you got a show this weekend, right?
你这周末有场演出，是吗？
Is it real?
这是真的吗？
We're announce in class on, on on Wednesday.
我们在星期三的课堂上宣布。
We have a lot to discuss, a lot to go over,
我们有很多事情要讨论，
so let's jump right into it.
所以，让我们直接开始吧。
So on the [] of you guys,
所以在你们的[]，
obviously project zero was was due last night,
项目 #0 昨晚就该交了，
we haven't gone through yet and looked at the results for everyone,
我们还没有完成，也没有看到每个人的结果，
I think we had about 150 something people completed,
我想我们有大约 150 人完成了，
that's good,
这很好，
project #1 has out and that'll be due on,
项目 #1 已经放出了，截至到，
sorry, homework #1 has been out for a while,
抱歉，家庭作业 #1 已经放出一段时间了，
but we bumped the deadline up to this 15th,
但我们将最后期限推迟到了 15 号，
four days from now,
也就是四天后，
so that should be reflected in Gradescope
所以这会在 Gradescope 反应出来，
and then project #1 is out and that'll be due on October 1st.
然后项目 #1 已经放出，将在 10 月 1 日截止。
Any questions about homework #1
任何关于家庭作业 #1 的问题，
and know there somebody there was somebody post on Piazza about project #1,
知道有人在 Piazza 上张贴了关于项目 #1 的帖子，
the leaderboard assignment doesn't work yet,
排行榜的作业还没有工作，
we're still, we're fixing that
我们仍然，我们正在解决这个问题，
and we'll push that on Github later, later, later, later this week,
我们会在本周晚些时候把它推送到 GitHub 上，
then I'll now it's on Wednesday what the leaderboard is,
然后我将在周三讨论排行榜是什么，
what the implications of it and why it matters.
它的含义是什么，为什么它很重要。
All right, the other thing, that's going on for for additional things,
好的，另外一件事，是额外的事情，
if you want to learn beyond the stuff we're talking about in the course,
如果你想学习我们在这门课上讨论的以外的东西，
there's a couple of database talks that are coming up,
接下来会有几场关于数据库的讨论，
so today after class at 4:30,
所以今天课后的 4:30 ，
we're having the the Qdrant guys, out of Germany,
我们有 Qdrant 的人，来自德国，
they're one of these vector databases,
它们是向量数据库之一，
that target LLMs or ChatGPT kind of setups,
针对 LLM 或 ChatGBT 之类的设置，
they'll be talking about their the internals of their system
他们将谈论他们系统的内部结构，
and that'll be again 4:30 over Zoom.
这将是在 4:30 ，通过 Zoom 。
Tomorrow at 6:00pm,
明天下午 6 点，
the Databricks people giving talks somewhere, somewhere in Gates Building,
Databricks 的人在盖茨大楼的某个地方开展讲座，
it's a recruiting talk,
这是一场招聘讲座，
but these are probably going to feed you
但这些可能会满足你的需求，
and then you can talk to them about getting jobs there,
然后你可以与他们谈论在那里找到工作的问题，
Databricks has hired pretty much almost all my best students in the last two or three years,
在过去的两三年里， Databricks 录取了几乎所有我最好的学生，
they've all gone to Databricks
他们都去了 Databricks ，
and I was there in July and they're all doing great,
我在 7 月份在那里，他们都做得很好，
they have a lot of money and they don't give us any.
他们有很多钱，但没有给我们任何钱。
And then OtterTune is actually my startup,
然后 OtterTune 是我的初创公司，
but my, my former PhD student, who's a co-founder with me, Dana Van Aken,
我以前的博士生，也是联合创始人， Dana Van Aken ，
she'll be giving a talk about,
她将发表演讲，
what, what we're doing using machine learning to optimize database systems, Postgres Mysql,
我们如何利用机器学习来优化数据库系统， Postgres MySQL ，
next week.
在下周。
Yes.
是的。
Where can we have information about the location.
我们在哪里找到关于地点的信息？
So my talks, the Qdrant one, OtterTune one, that's on Zoom,
所以我的演讲， Qdrant 这个， OtterTune 这个，是在 Zoom 上，
and then if you go on the slides,
然后如果你打开幻灯片，
the link here will take you to whatever it is on the calendar,
这里的链接会把你带到日程，
somewhere in Gates,
盖茨大楼的某个地方，
for the Databricks one.
对于 Databricks 这个。
Yep.
是的。
Other questions,
还有其他问题吗，
again these are optional,
这些也是可选的，
these are like, if you want to go beyond the stuff to talk about in the course.
如果你想要超越课程中要谈论的东西。
And what I like about these kind of talks is,
我喜欢这种演讲的地方是，
like even if you don't understand anything right away,
即使你现在什么都不懂，
we hit these a lot of these topics throughout the semester
我们整个学期都在谈论这些话题，
and then you realize I'm not crazy,
然后你就会意识到我并没有疯，
well, I'm crazy, but like not that crazy,
好吧，我是疯了，但不是那么疯狂，
that like I'm not making stuff up,
我不是在胡编乱造，
these are the things we're talking about in this semester,
这就是我们在本学期要讨论的内容，
You know, you need to know are applicable to building real systems.
你应该知道适用于建立真正的系统。
All right, so last class we talked about,
好的，上一节课我们谈到了，
you know, the initial setup for what the framework you're going to have in our minds
你们会有什么样的框架的初始设置，
for describing how we're going to build a database management system,
描述我们如何建立一个数据管理系统，
and we discussed how it was a disk-oriented architecture,
我们讨论了它如何成为面向磁盘的架构，
where all the components in the system are really based around this, this key premise,
其中系统中的所有组件都基于这一关键前提，
that the primary search location of the database,
数据库的主要搜索位置，
when is when it is at rest,
当它处于静止状态时，
will be on some, some non-volatile disk, right,
将位于某些非易失性磁盘上，
SSD, spinning disk hard drive, doesn't matter.
SSD ，旋转磁盘硬盘，并不重要。
And that the components of the system are really about
系统的组件实际上是，
moving the data back and forth between disk and memory,
在磁盘和内存之间来回移动数据，
because it's a Von Neumann architecture,
因为它是一个冯·诺伊曼架构，
you can't operate on it, while it's at rest, right.
当它处于静止状态时，你不能对其进行操作。
So that's really what the, the, the big picture of what we're trying to achieve.
所以，这就是我们试图实现的总体目标。
And of course now since disk is slow,
当然，现在由于磁盘速度很慢，
we need to do a bunch of tricks and a bunch of other techniques
我们需要使用一系列技巧和其他技术，
to, to hide the stalls of going to disk
来隐藏磁盘访问的停滞，
by maximizing amount of sequential IO.
通过最大化顺序 IO 的数量。
And we'll see in the beginning right away today,
我们今天一开始就会看到，
we'll talk about different method,
今天我们将讨论不同的方法，
an alternative to what we talked about last class,
这是我们上一节课讨论的另一种方法，
that tried to maximize sequential IO.
它试图最大化顺序 IO 。
And then again, there'll be other things like filters and indexes,
然后，还会有其他东西，比如过滤器和索引，
a way to reduce the amount of data we have to actually look at,
这是一种减少必须实际查看的数据量的方法，
when we run queries.
当我们在运行查询时。
Then we also talked about a page oriented storage scheme,
然后我们还讨论了一种面向页面的存储方案，
the slotted page architecture,
插槽页面架构，
where it would allow us to store tuples of arbitrary length, variable length sizes across these heap files
它允许我们在堆文件中存储任意长度、可变长度的 tuple ，
and then we could expand the the the size of the tuple as needed,
然后我们可以根据需要扩展 tuple 的大小，
you know, according to according to whether it fit in the page or not.
根据它是否适合页面。
All right.
好的。
So I would say what we were describing last time is,
所以我会说，我们上次所描述的是，
what I'll loosely term to as a tuple-oriented storage scheme,
我将粗略地称为面向 tuple 的存储方案，
what that really means is that,
这实际上意味着，
the, the system is really about,
这个系统实际上是关于，
I got a tuple, I got to put it somewhere, right,
我有一个 tuple ，我要把它放在某个地方，
and, and the pages of the layout, the layouts of the pages are really based around this,
页面的布局基于这一点，
like I got a tuple, like let me store it.
我有一个 tuple ，让我把它存储起来。
And so in this, in this architecture,
所以，在这个架构中，
if you wanted to insert a new tuple,
如果你想要插入一个新的 tuple ，
the way you would do it is,
你可以做的方法是，
you go look at the page directory
你可以查看页面目录，
and find somewhere in your heap files,
在堆文件中找到某个位置，
a page with a free slot,
一个有空闲插槽的页面，
we said that the page directory had maintained metadata
我们说页面目录维护了元数据，
about what what space is available.
关于哪些空间是可用的。
And then once we have our page, that we want to insert the tuple into,
然后一旦我们有了，我们想要插入 tuple 的页面，
if, if it's not memory,
如果这不是内存，
they got to go to disk and fetch it in,
他们就必须去磁盘获取它，
which we'll talk about next week,
我们将在下周讨论，
how we do that,
我们如何做到，
but think of reading a file, bringing the memory,
但是想想读取一个文件，带入内存，
and then once we have that page,
一旦我们有了那个页面，
we go look in that slot array
我们就去查看那个 slot array ，
and we say, you know, what's the next free slot, where we can store this tuple,
我们说，可以存储这个 tuple 的下一个空闲插槽是什么，
update the slot array, put the tuple inside the page,
更新 slot array ，将 tuple 放入页面中，
and then we're done.
然后我们就完成了。
To update a tuple in this environment is basically the same thing,
在这个环境中更新 tuple 基本上是相同的，
where we're going to have some way to get the record ID of a tuple,
我们将有一些方法来获得 tuple 的 record ID ，
we said this is typically the page ID and the offset or the slot number, right,
我们说这通常是页面 ID 和偏移量或插槽编号，
ignoring how we got that,
忽略我们如何获得它，
which which what index will do for us,
索引将为我们做什么，
ignoring, ignoring that, assume we could do that,
忽略它，假设我们可以做到，
we go, go in the page directory again,
我们再一次去页面目录，
find the location of this page,
找到这个页面的位置，
if it's in, if it's in memory, we're good,
如果它在内存中，我们就没问题了，
if not, we got to go disk and get it,
如果没有，我们就得去磁盘上拿到它，
then look at the page and the slot array, find the offset
然后查看页面和 slot array ，找到偏移量，
and then if the new tuple, we're trying to,
然后如果是新的 tuple ，
the updated tuple we're trying to install,
我们试图安装的更新 tuple ，
If that's the same size of the original tuple of existing tuple,
如果它与原始 tuple ，存在的 tuple 大小相同，
then we just overwrite it,
那么我们只需覆盖它，
if not, then maybe you got to find another page that could accommodate it,
如果没有，那么你可能需要找到另一个可以容纳它的页面，
if there's no space in the page we're looking at, right.
那么我们正在查看的页面中没有空间。
And this is the core of idea of, of what the heap files with page-oriented architecture,
这就是堆文件使用面向页面架构的核心理念，
and that's based on tuples,
这是基于 tuple 的，
this is basically how any system would actually work.
这基本上就是任何系统的实际运作方式。
So what are some problems with this,
那么，这有什么问题呢，
we touched on some of these last class,
我们在上一节课中，谈到了一些内容，
is it efficient,
它是高效的吗，
for reads, maybe, right,
对于读取，可能是，
right, because if I need the entire tuple,
因为如果我需要整个 tuple ，
I go to one page and get it,
我会去一个页面拿到它，
that's okay,
这是可以的，
but if I start updating things,
但是如果我开始更新某些内容，
I've started making writes, to do inserts, updates, deletes,
我开始写入操作，做插入、更新、删除，
I could end up with fragmentation in my pages, right,
我的页面可能会变得支离破碎，
I could have pages that are not fully utilized,
我可能有一些页面没有被充分利用，
meaning I I have a little empty space,
这意味着我有一点空闲空间，
where I can't fit any new tuple,
无法容纳任何新的 tuple ，
it's not big enough for a new tuple,
它不够大放下一个新的 tuple ，
so I can't use it, but it just wasted,
所以我不能用它，它就浪费了，
it's just there, right,
它就在那里，
or even before, you know, if I run that space,
甚至在之前，如果我运行那个空间，
if, if I have to insert a new tuple,
如果我必须插入一个新的 tuple ，
I got to allocate,
我必须分配，
you know, assuming I have nothing in my tuple,
假设我的 tuple 什么都没有，
I I insert it into tuple,
我把它插入到 tuple 中，
I allocate a page,
我分配一个页面，
I insert one tuple in that page,
我在那个页面中插入一个 tuple ，
there's nothing else on that page,
那一页上没有其他东西了，
again, depending on the size of my my page pages,
同样，根据我的页面大小，
which could be it's different for per systems,
每个系统的大小可能会有所不同，
there's a bunch empty space that's just not being used.
有一大堆空闲空间没有被使用。
Next challenge we face is as much useless disk I/O,
我们面临的下一个挑战是无用的磁盘 I/O ，
so if I got update one tuple,
所以，如果我更新一个 tuple ，
if it's not in memory,
如果它不在内存中，
I gotta go disk and fetch it,
我必须去磁盘上取回它，
but if it's in that side of that page,
但如果在那个页面的那一边，
what am I getting, right,
我能得到什么，
we're not storing one tuple per page,
我们不是每页存储一个 tuple ，
I mean, you could, but you typically don't want to do that,
我的意思是，你可以，但你通常不想这么做，
so now if I got to go update one page, sorry, a one tuple,
所以，现在如果我要去更新一个页面，抱歉，一个 tuple ，
I got to fetch that entire page and bring in a bunch of data,
我必须获取整个页面，并带来一堆数据，
that may not even be what I need,
这可能甚至不是我需要的，
because there's a bunch of other twoils that I'm not updating.
因为还有一堆其他的 tuple 我没有更新。
Same thing when I'm going to do a write,
当我要做写入的时候也是一样的，
if I'm only updating one tuple,
如果我只更新一个 tuple ，
I had to bring in 20 tuples in the page into memory,
我必须把这一页中的 20 个 tuple 带入内存中，
now I gotta write those 20 tuples back out.
现在我要把那 20 个 tuple 写回去。
And the last issue is that,
最后一个问题是，
we're going to get a potentially a lot of random disk I/O,
我们可能会得到大量随机磁盘 I/O ，
again the the sort of the [cop-out] answer
再说一次，一种[回避的]答案，
for people ask, like is this more efficient or which approach is better,
对于人们问的，这个更有效率，或者哪种方法更好，
the answer is, it always is depends in databases, right,
答案是，它总是取决于数据库。
so if your workload is only updating a single tuple at a time per query,
所以，如果你的工作负载是每次查询只更新一个 tuple ，
then maybe this architecture isn't so bad,
那么这个架构可能并不是那么糟糕，
but if I'm updating 20 tuples at a time
但如果我一次更新 20 个 tuple ，
and those 20 tuples are in 20 separate pages,
而这 20 个 tuple 在 20 个单独的页面中，
I got to go read 20 separate pages and, and from disk into memory,
我必须读取 20 个单独的页面，从磁盘到内存，
I got to update them
我必须更新它们，
and I got to write out 20 different pages in memory, sorry, from memory to disk,
我必须写出 20 个不同的页面到内存中，从内存到磁盘，
now that's random I/O,
这是随机 I/O ，
and that's going to be slower.
速度会更慢。
And then not necessarily a problem with the architecture itself,
然后不一定是架构本身的问题，
but it may be the case that we're operating in an environment,
但情况可能是，我们在一个环境中操作，
where we can't do those in place updates,
我们不能进行就地更新，
that we assume we could do in a slot of page architecture,
我们认为可以在页面架构中做的，
meaning I can't fetch a page that's in disk, bring it into memory,
这意味着我不能获取磁盘中的页面，将其放入内存，
update it and then write it back to where I got it from,
进行更新，然后将其写回原来的位置，
you can't do this in some cloud storage systems, right,
你不能在某些云存储系统中这样做，
S3, you can kind of trick it out using versioning,
S3 ，你可以使用版本控制来解决这个问题，
but like I can't do in place updates in some cloud database systems
但我不能在一些云数据库系统就地更新，
and the Hadoop file system, it's not that common anymore,
Hadoop 文件系统，这那么常见，
but that is another good example,
但这是另一个很好的例子，
of like that's a distributed a file system,
它是分布式文件系统，
where again I can't do in place updates,
我同样不能进行就地更新，
I can only do appends.
我只能做追加。
So this tuple-oriented [slide] of page architecture wouldn't work in this environment,
所以这个面向 tuple 的页面架构在这个环境中是不起作用的，
because I can't do,
因为我不能做，
I can't modify a page and write it back where I got.
我不能修改一个页面，然后把它写回我得到的地方。
So this is why we need to look at potentially alternative methods
所以，这就是为什么我们需要研究潜在的替代方法，
and in particular, all the problems I just talked about,
特别是我刚才谈到的所有问题，
they'll be solved with a log-structured storage scheme.
这些问题将通过日志结构存储方案来解决。
And beyond the heap file page architecture,
除了堆文件页面架构，
log-structured storage is probably the second most common approach people take in database systems,
日志结构存储可能是人们在数据库系统中采用的第二种最常见的方法，
it's probably even more common today,
这在今天可能更加常见，
because of embedded storage managers like RocksDB,
因为嵌入式存储管理器，比如 RocksDB ，
which are log structured.
它们是日志结构的。
So you ever seen a database system, that's using RocksDB,
你见过使用 RocksDB 的数据库系统吗，
they're inherently log-structured,
它们本质上是日志结构，
because RocksDB is log-structured.
因为 Rocksdb 是日志结构的。
And then we'll talk about another approach,
然后我们将讨论另一种方法，
not exactly log structured,
不完全是日志结构，
it sort of amalgamation of the two,
它是这两者的某种融合，
will be index-organized storage,
也就是面向索引的存储，
that's what MySQL and SQLite and others use.
这就是 MySQL 和 SQLite 以及其他所使用的。
And then we'll finish off talking about,
然后，我们将结束讨论，
how to actually represent the data of attributes in tuples.
如何实际表示 tuple 中的属性数据。
Again, we were working out what a file looks like, what a page looks like,
同样，我们研究文件的样子，页面的样子，
we're still sort of in that world,
我们仍然在那个世界里，
and then we'll spend more time talking about,
然后我们会花更多的时间来讨论，
what the actual individual tuples look like,
实际的单个 tuple 是什么样子的，
the values in the individual tuples.
在单个 tuple 中的值。
Okay?
好的？
All right.
好的。
All right, so log-structure storage is an old idea,
好的，所以日志结构存储是一个古老的想法，
it's loosely related to log-structured file systems,
它与日志结构文件系统有松散的关系，
which predates at about ten years,
（日志文件系统）早了大约十年，
log-structure file systems, like in 1980s,
日志结构文件系统，大约在 1980 年代，
the log-structured storage of was first proposed in the in the mid 90s,
日志结构存储最早是在 90 年代中期提出的，
actually in the textbook,
实际上，在课本中，
they'll call log-structured merge trees,
他们称为日志结构合并树，
I'm not going to describe what what the actual log-structure merge trees looks like,
我不打算描述日志结构合并树是什么样子的，
because I don't think you need to know the details of the tree part of it, right,
因为我认为你不需要知道它的树部分的细节。
so I, I'll describe basically the same idea, but without bringing in the tree,
所以我将描述基本上相同的想法，但没有引入树，
because that makes makes things more complicated.
因为这会使事情变得更加复杂。
But the high level idea is what I care about,
但高层次的想法才是我所关心的，
what I want you guys understand.
是我想让你们明白的。
So the basic idea of log-structure storage is that,
所以，日志结构存储的基本思想是，
instead of storing individual tuples,
不是存储单独的 tuple ，
we're going to maintain a log record of the changes to those tuples,
我们将维护对 tuple 修改的日志记录，
I think it's a key value store, key value system,
我认为这是一个键值存储，键值系统，
so I'm going to have some operation, either just PUT and DELETE,
所以我要做一些操作， PUT 和 DELETE ，
and then I'm going to have a key value pair
然后我将有一个键值对，
with the key corresponding to some tuple identifier,
其中的键对应于某个 tuple 的标识符，
we can't use the record ID we did before,
我们不能使用以前使用的 record ID ，
because we're not going to have pages,
因为我们不会有页面，
we not going to have all [sets] and slots,
我们不会有所有的[集合]和插槽，
so we're not, it's not going be that,
所以它不会是那样，
but it'll be some key identifier,
但它会是一些键标识符，
and then the payload would be here's the actual tuples itself,
然后有效负载将是实际的 tuple 本身，
that I'm trying to, you know, install for in the PUT.
我试图在 PUT 中安装。
And so as the application inserts data makes changes,
所以，当应用程序插入数据进行更改时，
we're going to append new log entries to an in-memory buffer,
我们将把新的日志条目追加到内存缓冲区中，
just in the order that they arrive
按照它们到达的顺序，
and then at some point that buffer is going to get full
然后在某个时候缓冲区会变满，
and we're going to write it out the disk.
我们要把它写到磁盘上。
Pretty simple, right?
很简单，对吧？
All right, so let's see an example here,
好的，让我们来看一个例子，
so again, the only two operations we're going to have are PUT and DELETE, right,
我们要做的只有两个操作， PUT 和 DELETE ，
there's no insert, because that's just a PUT there,
这里没有插入，因为那只有一个 PUT ，
there's no update,
这里没有更新，
because that just PUT, you doing blind write over top of whatever was there before.
因为 PUT 只是盲目地写入在之前的任何东西上。
And so in our log file in memory, right,
所以，在内存中的日志文件中，
we're going to go from oldest to newest,
我们将从最旧到最新，
so at the beginning of the file or beginning of the buffer,
所以，在文件的开头或缓冲区的开头，
that'll be the oldest entries
这将是最旧的条目，
and we're just appending to them as we make changes, right.
我们只是追加它们，当我们做出修改时。
So the application may say,
所以应用程序可能会说，
I want to go ahead and do a PUT on record 103,
我想继续，做一个 PUT 在记录 103 上，
where the 103 came from, we don't care,
103 的来自哪里，我们不在乎，
assuming that some other upper part of the system that figured that, figured that out for us,
假设系统的其他上层为我们解决了这一问题，
and then again, the payload in the, in the log record would be,
然后，日志记录中的有效负载是，
we're setting the value to whatever record 103 is to to 1, a1.
我们将记录 103 的值设置为 a1 。
Same thing, next next guy comes along,
同样的事情，下一个出现了，
he wants to do a PUT a 104
他想做一个 PUT 到 104 ，
and then updates that record, right.
然后更新那个记录，
And then if we have a DELETE,
然后，如果我们有一个 DELETE ，
we, we just delete, have a DELETE operation in a log record
我们在日志记录中有 DELETE 操作，
and then with the same tuple identifier,
然后使用相同的 tuple 标识符，
keep it appending to the log as we go along, right.
随着我们继续，将它追加到日志中，
So in this example here,
所以在这个例子中，
we don't need to go actually read what the original record was,
我们并不需要去读取原始记录是什么，
the original tuple was,
原始的 tuple 是什么，
anytime we want to update the log.
任何时候我们想要更新日志。
Again, think of the lower [] of the system,
想想这个系统的下层，
obviously, if I'm doing a query,
显然，如果我要执行查询，
like update, update table, set ID,
比如更新表设置 ID ，
or set value equals value plus one,
或者设置值等于值加一，
I got to know what the original value was,
我必须知道原始值是什么，
and that's essentially doing a read followed by a write,
这实质上就是先读后写，
but at this lowest level of the system,
但在这个系统的最低层，
we don't know, we don't have to know,
我们不需要知道，
what the original value was for a given, given key.
给定的键的原始值是多少。
And again, that's different than the tuple-oriented architecture,
同样，这与面向 tuple 的架构不同，
where I had to go fetch the page, that had the original tuple
在那里，我必须获取包含原始 tuple 的页面，
and then I can update it,
然后才能更新它，
I don't have to do that with this, right.
在这里，我不用这么做。
So again, at some point this thing will get, this in-memory page will get full,
在某个时刻，内存中页面会变满，
and we got to write it out the disk,
我们必须将其写到磁盘，
and that's literally just taking the entire contents of the memory page
这就是获取内存页的全部内容，
and plopping it down to a bunch of pages on disk,
并将其[拖到]磁盘上的一堆页中，
clear out my memory buffer,
清空我的内存缓冲区，
and then start filling it up with new log entries,
然后开始用新的日志条目填充它，
and then when that gets full,
然后当它变满的时候，
same thing, I write that out.
同样的事情，我把它写出去。
Now, important thing about this,
现在，关于这一点，重要的是，
there are just two important things to point out,
有两件重要的事情需要指出，
when we do this, right.
当我们做这个的时候。
First of all, this is all sequential I/O now, right,
首先，这一切现在都是顺序 I/O ，
because my, my, my in-memory page could be a megabyte or ten megabytes,
因为我的内存中页面可能是 1 兆字节或者 10 兆字节，
when that gets full,
当它变满时，
I write out sequentially those ten megabytes to the file on disk.
我将这 10 兆字节按顺序写出到磁盘上的文件中。
So no matter, again in the tuple-oriented architecture or the page-oriented architecture,
所以，无论是在面向 tuple 架构或面向页面架构中，
where I would have, you know, 20 tuples spread across 20 different pages,
我都会有 20 个 tuple 分布在 20 个不同的页面上。
In this, in this environment, with this setup,
在这种环境中，在这种设置下，
those 20 tuples are always going to be on the same page,
这 20 个 tuple 总是在同一页面上，
when I write them out,
当我写出它们时，
because there's appending log records.
因为这是追加日志记录。
The other important thing in this architecture is that,
这个架构中的另一件重要事情是，
once a page is written to disk, it's immutable,
一旦将页面写入磁盘，它就是不可变的，
meaning we can never go back and do in place updates,
这意味着我们永远不能回去做原地更新，
we'll compact it,
我们会压缩它，
we'll see that in a second, basically do garbage collection,
我们很快就会看到，基本上就是垃圾回收，
but we never can overwrite a log record that was already there before,
但我们永远不能覆盖以前已经存在的日志记录，
we're not caught distributed databases just yet,
我们现在还不了解分布式数据库，
but there is some advantage to making sure your files are immutable
但是确保你的文件是不变的是有一些好处的，
and ignoring the like, oh, well, if I'm on a cloud storage, I can't do in place updates,
忽略比如，如果我在云存储上，我不能进行就地更新，
but it does make it easy now,
但它现在确实容易了，
if it's just appending the log,
如果它只是附加日志，
that's essentially what Paxos or something a Raft is doing,
这本质上就是 Paxos 或 Raft 所做的，
adding log, log records and never go back and making changes.
添加日志记录，永远不会回去和进行更改。
It could change in the log would be a new log entry, right.
它可以修改日志，将是新的日志条目。
So this makes the architecture a lot easier,
所以，这将使架构变得容易很多，
once it's on disk and you don't update it.
一旦存储在磁盘上，并且不需要更新，
Now, for now, we're going to ignore,
现在，我们将忽略，
what happens if I need to write the memory buffer out,
如果我需要写出内存缓冲区，
before I want to, before it's, you know, completely full,
在它完全满之前，
like if I have running a query or transaction,
比如，如果我运行一个查询或事务，
that, that wants to make sure that my changes are written to disk,
希望确保将我的更改写入磁盘，
before I tell the outside world, that the data is safely written to disk,
在我告诉外界，数据被安全地写入磁盘之前，
I may write this log buffer out,
我可能会写出这个日志缓冲区，
before it's finished, before it's full,
在它完成之前，在它装满之前，
but I'll write it to a separate location,
但我会把它写到一个单独的位置，
a local disk, where I can do these kind of writes.
一个本地磁盘，在那里我可以进行这种写操作。
But again, we'll ignore that for now.
但是，我们现在将忽略这个。
All right, again, so in the log-structure architecture,
好的，所以，在日志结构架构中，
that's going to make our writes really fast,
这将使我们的写入速度非常快，
much faster than a tuple-oriented architecture,
比面向 tuple 的结构快得多，
because again, we're just appending log records
因为，我们只是追加日志记录，
and we write them out sequentially.
并按顺序写出它们。
What's potentially going to be slower now?
现在什么可能会变得更慢？
Reads.
读取。
Again, in computer science and database systems, there's no free lunch,
在计算机科学和数据库系统中，没有免费的午餐，
so we're making the writes go faster,
所以我们让写入更快，
but now the reads potentially go slower.
但现在读取可能会变得更慢。
So to do a read, what do we have to do,
那么，为了读取，我们必须做些什么，
well, again, assuming, assuming something in our system has figured out,
好的，假设我们系统中的某些东西已经计算出，
you know, the ID or the key of the, the log record, I want,
ID 或我需要的日志记录的键，
like 102, 103, 104,
比如 102 103 104 ，
we can ignore that for now,
我们现在可以忽略它，
in order for us to find the log record for a given key,
为了我们找到给定键的日志记录，
we first want to check the in-memory page,
我们首先要检查内存中的页面，
start at the end, because that's the newest records,
从末尾开始，因为这是最新的记录，
and just scan sequentially in reverse order,
然后以相反的顺序顺序扫描，
going back to the beginning,
返回到开头，
until we find the log entry that we want,
直到我们找到我们想要的日志条目，
if it's not there,
如果它不在那里，
we may have to go to disk,
我们可能不得不去磁盘，
we'll cover that in a second.
我们稍后会讲到这个。
So is this efficient?
那么，这是高效的吗？
No, right.
不是。
So a way to get around this,
所以，绕过这个的一种方法，
and this is where that log structure merge tree in the textbook comes in,
这就是教科书中日志结构合并树的来源，
but again, we don't have to worry about the details,
但同样，我们不必担心细节，
is that they're going to maintain some kind of index, right,
它们将维护某种类型的索引，
for every single record ID,
对于每个 record ID ，
it'll tell you where in the in-memory buffer page is located,
它将告诉你内存缓冲区页面中的位置，
or if it's not in memory, where is it on disk, right.
或者如果它不在内存中，那么它在磁盘上的哪里，
So to get record ID 104,
所以，要获得 record ID 104 ，
I would just do some lookup in this index,
我只需在这个索引中进行一些查找，
I'm not telling you what data structure it is, doesn't matter,
我不会告诉你它是什么数据结构，无关紧要，
it's typically going to be a B+ tree,
它通常会是 B+ 树，
but some systems use just Trie, some systems use skip list,
但是一些系统使用 Trie ，一些系统使用跳表，
it doesn't matter,
无所谓，
do my look up and find 104
做我的查找，查找 104 ，
and then I'll tell you what offset in the memory page,
然后我会告诉你内存页面的偏移量是多少，
the memory buffer has the data that I'm looking for.
内存缓冲区里有我要找的数据。
In the case, I want to look at 103,
在这种情况下，我想查看 103 ，
then I got to go out the disk and get it.
然后我必须去磁盘，并获得它。
All right.
好的。
So far, so good?
到现在为止还好吗？
So your question is,
所以，你的问题是，
is it possible to implement the index in the append only file system?
是否可能在仅追加的文件系统中实现索引？
So, so, yeah.
所以，是的。
So the way you would do this is like,
所以你这样做的方式就像是，
you can sort of just treat this as a log itself
你可以把它当作一个日志本身，
and then you then in memory you build a data structure on top of it,
然后你在内存中在它上面构建一个数据结构，
so like in a B+ tree
比如在 B+ 树中，
and a typically typically is done is like,
典型的操作类似于，
when you write the pages at the disk,
当你在磁盘上写入页面时，
you're still maintaining the the data structure itself,
你仍在维护数据结构本身，
like the pointers between the children and parents and so forth,
比如孩子和双亲之间的指针等，
in, in this, this environment,
在这种环境中，
you would basically reconstruct the in-memory index by replaying the log,
你可以通过重放日志来重建内存中的索引，
so you could do it in a readonly file system.
这样你就可以在只读文件系统中执行此操作。
Actually, I don't know what RocksDB does.
事实上，我不知道 RocksDB 所做的。
Yes.
是的。
So the question is,
所以问题是，
is this index the same index,
这个索引是不是相同的索引，
you would get when you run CREATE INDEX in SQLite.
当你在 SQLite 中运行 CREATE INDEX 时得到的。
And specifically SQLite, no.
特别指 SQLite ，不是。
Well, SQLite not log-structured,
好的， SQLite 不是日志结构的，
you basically is this the same index as a primary key index,
你是说，这与主键索引相同吗，
potentially, yes, but not always, right,
可能，是的，但并不总是，
SQL is kind of complicated,
SQL 有点复杂，
they index of pages
页面索引，
and you can have the non index, non table indexes
你可以有非表索引，
and then the primary key table indexes,
然后主键表索引，
give me a second, we'll get to that.
给我一点时间，我们会讲到这个。
Think of this as like,
把这个想象成这样，
it's almost like the internal bookkeeping of find, the find records,
它几乎就像查找记录的内部记账，
almost like the page directory,
几乎就像页面目录，
it's not something you would necessarily expose to the SQL queries themselves,
这不是你必须向 SQL 查询本身公开的内容，
but you could, you could use them for that.
但你可以使用它们。
So your question is, you statement is,
所以你的问题是，
this index is pointing to things that happen in memory,
这个索引指向的是发生在内存中的事情，
which is not true, right,
这不是真的，
it could point to the disk.
它可以指向磁盘。
Why do we store everything down here,
为什么我们要存储所有东西，
we'll do that in a second,
我们马上就会做这个，
but, in this case here,
但是，在这个例子中，
I have ID equals 103,
我有 ID 等于 103 ，
it's not in memory, it's somewhere's on disk,
它不在内存中，它在磁盘上的某个地方，
so, but where, right,
那么，在哪里，
I can't just [blow away] the whole file,
我不能丢弃整个文件，
I would have to pull it out, right,
我得把它拿出来，
and that's expensive and that's compaction,
它是昂贵的，它是压缩的，
we'll get that in a second.
我们稍后会讲到这个。
Yes.
是的。
His statement is,
他的说法是，
why do we need to store this DEL record,
为什么我们需要存储这个 DEL 记录，
if it's, if it's been deleted, why even store that.
如果它已经被删除了，为什么还要保存它。
Because there's gonna be a PUT,
因为这里会有 PUT ，
for like this, say 102, there's a PUT before it, right,
比如 102 ，有一个 PUT 在它前面，
but say there was another PUT that got written at the disk,
但是假如另一个 PUT 已经写在磁盘上，
I again, think of like, I'm going back in time
想象我回到过去，
and I want to make sure that,
我想确保，
if I don't have that delete, then it does exist, right,
如果我没有删除，那么它确实存在，
because I can't go back
因为我不能回去，
and okay, 102 got deleted,
好的， 102 被删除了，
let me find a page where it's in and pull it out,
让我找一个它所在的页面，然后把它拉出来，
I can't do that,
我不能那么做，
so I just append a log record and say,
所以我追加一个日志记录，说，
okay, if you're going back in time and you see 102,
好的，如果你回到过去，查看 102 ，
no, it's been deleted.
它已经被删除了。
And we'll coalesce them in a second
我们将在稍后将它们合并，
to remove the extra entries of those things.
以删除这些内容的多余条目。
Okay, so as both these guys sort of alluded to is like,
好的，就像这两个人提到的那样，
well, some of these log records, we don't need to maintain these forever, right,
一些日志记录，我们不需要永远维护它们，
and DELETE was example of this,
DELETE 就是这样的例子，
or PUTs over the same key over and over again, right.
或者 PUT 一遍又一遍地在同一个键上。
And so in a log-structured database system,
所以，在日志结构数据库系统中，
what they're going to do is,
他们要做的是，
they're periodically going to run some background job,
定期运行一些后台作业，
that will compact the pages,
用来压缩页面，
to, to coalesce them to reduce redundant operations.
把它们结合起来，减少多余的操作。
So in this case here,
在这个例子中，
I have page one, one and page two,
我有页面 #1 和页面 #2 ，
think of this going as newest to oldest, sorry, oldest to newest,
这是从最新到最旧，抱歉，最旧到最新，
so this one is older than this one
所以这个比这个旧，
and so if I want to compact them,
所以如果我想压缩它们，
then all you need to do is,
那么你需要做的就是，
recognize that here are the latest entries that I care about
这是我关心的最新条目，
for the keys that are referenced in these two pages, right,
对于这两个页面中引用的键，
so 103, 104
所以 103 104 ，
and then we DELETE 101 and 102
然后我们删除 101 和 102 ，
and then the PUT 105, right,
然后放入 105 ，
again, so there's a PUT 105 here,
这里有一个 PUT 105 ，
but because this is newer than this 105,
但是因为这个比这个 105 更新，
we know we don't,
我们知道我们不需要，
we want this one, not this one,
我们想要这个，而不是这个，
so instead of storing PUT 105,
所以不需要存储两个 105 ，
we only need to store one, in our coalesce pages.
我们只需要存储一个，在我们的合并页面中。
And as, as he brought up as well,
正如他也提到的，
like, it may be the case that,
情况可能是，
I actually don't need to store the DELETEs at this point as well,
我不需要在这一点上存储 DELETE ，
because there's some other upper part of the system,
因为系统上的其他部分，
that says all I've removed 102 101 from my index,
表明我已经从索引中删除了 102 101 ，
so anybody does a lookup, they'll see a key not found
任何人查找，他们会看到键没有找到，
and therefore I don't need to store the log entry for this.
所以我不需要存储这个日志条目。
So this is called compaction
这就是所谓的压缩，
and this is again, no free lunch,
同样，这也没有免费午餐，
the log, the log-structured storage is going to make the inserts much faster,
日志结构存储将使插入速度更快，
because it's just appending to the log,
因为它只追加日志，
but at some point, we're going to have to go clean things up.
但在某个时刻，我们必须去清理东西。
All right, so again, the idea is that,
好的，所以我们的想法是，
we we do this compaction,
我们做这种压缩，
now we down, now we're down to a, a compressed form of the, of the log of record,
现在我们得到日志记录的压缩形式，
and this is only on disk,
这只是在磁盘上，
we can't do in place updates,
我们无法进行就地更新，
so this is literally taking one disk page, another disk page
这就是取一个磁盘页，另一个磁盘页，
and then writing out a new one,
然后写出一个新的，
we can't overwrite an existing one.
我们不能覆盖现有的。
Another important thing to keep track of too is that,
另一件需要跟踪的重要事情是，
once it's on disk,
一旦它存储在磁盘上，
we know that it's going to be older than,
我们就知道它旧于，
once we have a page on disk,
一旦我们在磁盘上有了一个页面，
and once we've already compacted it,
并且我们已经压缩了它，
removing the redundant or the operations own the same key over and over again,
删除多余的或拥有相同的键的反复操作，
that means that within a disk page we've compacted,
这意味着在我们压缩的磁盘页中，
it only contains, or each key is only going to be referenced once,
它只包含，或者每个键只被引用一次，
at this point, we don't care about the the temporal ordering anymore in the log,
在这一点上，我们不再关心日志中的时间顺序，
we don't care about newest to oldest, right.
我们不关心最新到最旧。
So now if the operation we need to support is
所以现在如果我们需要支持的操作是
go find the key 103, 104 105 or whatever in the disk,
在磁盘上找出键 103 104 105 ，
the temporal order doesn't help us,
时间顺序对我们没有帮助，
and actually what we want to do is
实际上，我们要做的是，
sort the disk pages, sort the keys based sort,
对磁盘页进行排序，基于键进行排序，
sort the records of, the log records in the, in the this page based on the keys, right.
根据键对此页中的日志记录进行排序。
So we do something like this,
所以我们这样做，
because again, now all I need to know now is,
因为，现在我需要知道的是，
if I'm looking at this, this page,
如果我看着这个页面，
I know that these pages are older than each other,
我知道这些页面比其他页面更老，
so I have sort of some meta like that,
所以我有一些类似的元数据，
but each log record, I don't need to know whether one's older than another.
但每个日志记录，我不需要知道一个比另一个更老。
So when you do this compaction
所以当你做压缩的时候，
and then you sort them based on the key values,
然后你根据键值对它们进行排序，
these are sometimes called Sorted String Tables or SSTables,
这些有时被称为排序字符串表或 SSTables ，
I think this, this, this term is coined by Jeff Dean and the Sandjay guy,
我想这个术语是 Jeff Dean 和 Sandjay 创造的，
when they wrote LevelDB at Google,
当他们在谷歌写 LevelDB 时，
this is for, for bigtable in the, in the mid 2000s.
这是为了 2000 年中期的 bigtable 。
And the again, the advantage of this is that,
这样做的好处是，
when I have to go fetch this page in,
当我要去取这一页时，
I'm not looking for,
我不会去找，
like give me, give me the PUT for 103 this timestamp,
比如给我这个时间戳的 103 的 PUT ，
you're just looking for PUT 103,
你只是查找 PUT 103 ，
and so you want to do a lookup to find that that record as quickly as possible,
所以你需要尽快找到那个记录，
and so if you're sorted,
如果你进行了排序，
you can then build an index or a filter some way
你可以以某种方式构建索引或过滤器，
to quickly jump to that record you're looking for,
快速跳到你要查找的记录，
rather than having to do binary search across the entire file.
而不必在整个文件中执行二分搜索。
So there's some metadata and the header for each of these SSTable pages,
所以有一些元数据和每个 SSTable 页的 header ，
that keeps track of,
跟踪，
sorry, files, comprise multiple pages,
抱歉，由多个页面组成的文件，
that will keep track of where the, where the offsets are for the different keys.
跟踪不同键的偏移量在哪里。
Yes.
是的。
The question is,
问题是，
wouldn't the index that we're talking about to the exact, the exact location of where something is,
我们所讨论的索引不是准确地对应东西所在的位置吗，
not necessarily, you may want to keep the,
不一定，你可能想要保持，
you may want to keep a more [] index that says,
你可能想要保持一个更[]的索引，它说，
you know, here's not maybe the exact offset of the thing you're looking for,
这里可能不是你要找的东西的确切偏移量，
but here's the page, here's the file that has it,
但这是页面，这是包含它的文件，
and once you get to that file,
一旦你找到那个文件，
it'll tell you where to find it.
它会告诉你在哪里找到它。
Yeah, so maybe I'm not drawn a good example here,
是的，也许我在这里没有画出一个很好的例子，
so this I'm saying this page,
我要说的是，这个页面，
this could be multiple pages for SSD file
这可以是 SSD 文件的多个页面，
and typically because these things get big,
通常是因为这些内容变大了，
so it's not going to be a single page.
所以它是单个页面。
In the back, yes.
后面的，是的。
For the SSTable or the one back in memory?
对于 SSTable 还是内存中的？
Back in memory.
内存中的。
Yes, because you don't want to have to recreate it upon restart,
是的，因为你不想在重新启动时重新创建它，
and as I was saying it before,
正如我之前所说的，
either you could just write the file, the pages themselves to disk,
你可以只将文件和页面本身写入磁盘，
or you could just maintain a log record that says,
也可以只维护一个日志记录，它说，
here's how to rebuild the index.
以下是如何重建索引。
Yes. Why don't we write
是的。
Yes, the question is,
是的，问题是，
why don't we write the pages in sort of order,
为什么我们不按某种顺序来写这些页，
that's what they do.
这就是他们所做的。
Yes.
是的。
Absolutely yes,
绝对是的，
so his statement is and he's right,
所以他的陈述是正确的，
isn't compaction gonna have a impact on on the performance of the reads,
压缩不会对读取的性能产生影响吗，
because not only you're just taking locks, locks,
因为你不仅仅是拿着锁，
you're doing disk I/Os, right,
你在做磁盘 I/O ，
because now you're like you're, you're,
因为现在你在，
we'll get to different types of compaction a second,
我们稍后会看到不同类型的压缩，
now, you're potentially bringing in gigabytes of files in,
现在，你可能会带入吉字节的文件，
compacting it and writing them back out,
压缩文件，并将其写回，
so absolutely yes.
所以绝对是的。
Again, no free lunch.
再说一次，没有免费的午餐。
Okay.
好的。
So there, there's sort of two main ways you can do compaction,
有两种主要方法可以进行压缩，
and this terminology here I'll use is what use in RocksDB.
这里我将使用的术语是 RocksDB 中使用的。
So, the most simplest form is called Universal Compaction,
所以，最简单的形式被称为万能压缩，
where you're just taking adjacent sort of log files that are on disk,
你只需要取磁盘上相邻的日志文件，
again, this multiple pages, think of again, megabytes, gigabytes, terabytes,
同样，多个页面，考虑兆字节、吉字节、太字节，
and then you just want to take two, two, two, sort of, sort of log files that are adjacent
然后你只需要取两个相邻的日志文件，
and then compact them, right,
然后压缩它们，
so I would take these two guys, basically do a sort merge,
所以我取这两个，做一个排序合并，
well, they're already sorted,
它们已经排序了，
so now I'm just doing a merge
所以现在我只是做一次合并，
and figure out whether, you know, whether the different keys you're looking at,
看看是否你查找的不同的键，
whether one is subsumed by another,
是否一个包含另一个，
assuming that this one I said this one's older than this one,
假设这个比这个旧，
so if I see an update or PUT for key 103 here and a key 103 there,
如果我看到更新或 PUT ，对于这里的 103 和那里的 103 ，
then I know I want that one
那么我知道我想要那个，
and I can throw the other one away, right.
我可以扔掉另一个。
And I can do the same thing for any possible combination of these these sort of log files,
我可以对这些日志文件的任何可能组合执行相同的操作，
I can keep coding [] them into more compact forms.
我可以继续把它们编码成更紧凑的形式。
Another approach is do what it's called Level Compaction,
另一种方法是进行所谓的水平压缩，
again, this is what the Level and LevelDB comes from.
同样，这也是 LevelDB 的来源。
Actually, who here has heard of LevelDB,
实际上，在座的谁听说过 LevelDB ，
very few here,
这里没几个人，
here has heard of RocksDB,
谁听说过 RocksDB ，
more, okay, about not much more.
更多，好的，不会太多。
RocksDB is, is Facebook's fork LevelDB,
RocksDB 是 Facebook 对 LevelDB 的 fork ，
Google wrote LevelDB, RocksDB forked it,
谷歌写了 LevelDB ， RocksDB fork 了它，
the very first thing they did remove mmap, right,
他们做的第一件事就是删除了 mmap ，
and then they expanded it
然后他们扩展了它，
and did did a bunch of other stuff,
做了一系列其他的事情，
and so this Level Compaction comes from, from LevelDB.
所以这个水平压缩来自 LevelDB 。
All right, so you have your sort of file in disk
好的，所以你有文件在磁盘上，
and at level zero, they're going to be a certain size
在零级，它们将是一定的大小，
and you keep adding more sort, sort of files
你一直在添加更多的文件，
until some point you run compaction
直到某一点，你运行压缩，
and then you'll combine them down into a larger file at the next level, right,
然后你将它们组合成一个更大的文件，在下一个级别，
make, make, keep, make more of them at the top level
在顶层制造更多的它们，
and at some point that get merged together,
并在某个时候合并在一起，
and once I have enough at the next level,
一旦我在下一级足够多，
then I'll run compaction for that one
然后我会对那个进行压缩，
and produce something at the lower level,
并在较低的级别产生一些东西，
so sort of cascading down,
所以在某种程度上是层级式下降的，
I'm getting larger and larger files as I go down.
随着我的下降，文件越来越大。
All right, so as I said,
所以正如我所说的，
because RocksDB has sort of become the default choice for a lot of database vendors,
因为 RocksDB 已经成为许多数据库供应商的默认选择，
database, people building database systems,
人们构建数据库系统，
as like the, like of like the underlying storage manager to, to use,
作为要使用的底层存储管理器，
they're essentially log-structured,
它们本质上是日志结构的，
but then what they're building top of RocksDB is
但他们在 RocksDB 上构建的是，
all the SQL parsing layer, the SQL execution, the indexes,
所有的 SQL 解析层， SQL 执行，索引，
all the additional things we'll talk about throughout the semester.
所有我们将在整个学期讨论的其他内容。
And like RocksDB is essentially just providing a key value API,
RocksDB 本质上只提供键值 API ，
like you don't,
你不需要，
in, in, in my examples here,
在我的例子中，
I just said here's the value,
我只说这是值，
here's the payload I'm putting out to storing in, in the, in the log,
这是我要存储在日志中的有效负载，
it has no notion of attributes or columns, right,
它没有属性或列的概念，
so even though I say I ten columns in my table,
即使我说我的表中有 10 列，
but I only update one of them,
但我只更新了其中的一列，
my PUT record has to contain all ten columns.
我的 PUT 记录必须包含所有 10 列。
We'll see multi versioning how later in the semester after the midterm,
我们将在期中考试后看到多版本控制，
we can be smarter with this,
我们可以更聪明地使用它，
which essentially looks a lot like log-structure storage,
它看起来很像日志结构存储，
but for now we can ignore that.
但现在我们可以忽略它。
This is almost how Postgres,
这几乎就是 Postgres ，
this is how Postres was originally envisioned in the 1980s,
这就是 Postgres 在 1980 年代最初设想的，
it looked a lot like this.
它看起来很像这样。
So they said RocksDB is is super popular,
所以他们说 RocksDB 是非常流行的，
LevelDB and it's a fork of LevelDB
LevelDB ，它是 LevelDB 的 fork ，
and this is just a sampling of of different companies,
这只是部分不同公司，
that are using using a log-structure storage,
使用了日志结构存储，
again, some are based on RocksDB,
有些是以 RocksDB 为基础的，
CockroachDB originally started off using RocksDB,
CockroachDB 最初是使用 RocksDB ，
they threw it away and wrote their own thing in Go called Pebble,
他们把它扔掉，使用 Go 写了自己的东西，叫做 Pebble ，
Cassandra has their own log-structure storage,
Cassandra 有自己的日志结构存储，
TiDB has TiKV,
TiDB 有 TiKV ，
I think Dgraph uses BadgerDB,
我想 Dgraph 使用 BadgerDB ，
but a bunch of these [in], these these log-structure systems.
但是很多这些都使用日志结构系统。
So we already said the reads are slower,
我们已经说过读取速度较慢，
but what are some other problems,
但是还有哪些其他问题，
we would have with log-structure storage,
我们使用日志结构存储，
we said read was slower and the compactionum is expensive,
我们说过读取速度较慢，压缩昂贵，
there's one more core issue with this approach.
这种方法还有一个核心问题。
Yes.
是的。
it seems less disk efficient.
它的磁盘效率似乎较低。
What do you mean, what do you mean, what do you mean disk efficient?
你说的磁盘效率是什么意思？
Like you have to store extra copies of every tuple
比如你必须存储每个 tuple 的额外副本，
and when you compact, you have to create,
当你压缩时，你必须新建，
like you have to use other parts of disk, so.
你必须使用磁盘的其他部分，所以。
So the statement is that,
所以他的说法是，
it's less deficient,
它的效率不高，
because you have to store, [pitching] multiple copies of, of a tuple,
因为你必须存储一个 tuple 的多个副本，
because there's a bunch of PUT for them,
因为有一堆 PUT ，
and then when you do compaction,
然后当你进行压缩时，
you basically have to have a staging area,
你必须有一个临时区域，
more or less where you you have the two original files,
或多或少你有两个原始文件，
you're trying to compact two or more,
你试图压缩两个或更多，
and then you're writing out a new one, yes.
然后你写出一个新的，是的。
We say yes, that's an issue, yes.
我们说是，这是一个问题，是的。
But what about the, related to this point of compaction, what am I doing,
但是与这个压缩相关，我在做什么，
well, at some point earlier,
在早些时候的某个时候，
I had these log records in memory,
我在内存中保存了这些日志记录，
I wrote out the disk,
我写出到磁盘中，
now for compaction, what am I doing?
现在对于压缩，我在做什么。
Reading it back into memory, writing back out the disk.
将其读回内存，再写回磁盘。
So this is called Write-Amplification.
所以，这称为写入放大。
And the idea is that, the issue is that,
这里的问题是，
for every sort of logical write, I do my application,
对于每一种逻辑写入，我的应用程序所做的，
insert a tuple, update a single tuple,
插入一个 tuple ，更新一个 tuple ，
how many times am I going to read and write it back to disk,
我要读取和写回磁盘多少次，
and in a log-structure approach, potentially infinite, right,
以一种日志结构方法，可能是无限的，
If I just keep compacting, compacting over and over again,
如果我继续压缩，一遍又一遍地压缩，
obviously that doesn't, doesn't happen,
显然这不会发生，
but, I could potentially do,
但是，我可能会做，
for a single logical write, I could do dozens of physical writes,
对于一个逻辑写入，我可能会做几十次物理写入，
because I'm bringing back a memory and writing it back out.
因为我要带回到内存，然后把它写回出去。
And in the page architecture with slotted pages,
在使用插槽页面的页面架构中，
we don't have this problem,
我们没有这个问题，
when I do update a single tuple,
当我更新一个单独的 tuple 时，
I bring in a memory, I update it, I write it back out,
我会引入内存，更新它，然后写回它，
and then if I never update it again, I never write it out again,
如果我不再更新它，也不再把它写出去，
we ignore backup, we ignore the write ahead log,
我们忽略了备份，我们忽略了预先日志，
we'll get to that later in the semester,
我们将在本学期晚些时候讨论这个问题，
but if I don't, if I'm not, I'm not reading, I'm not using it,
但是，如果我没有读取，我没有使用它，
I'm not bringing the memory and and writing back out,
我不会把它带入内存再带回，
in a log-structure storage, you have to.
在日志结构存储中，你必须这样做。
Okay?
好的？
So again, if you want to go beyond this,
所以，如果你想超越这一点，
there's the log structure merge tree part of the textbook,
教科书中的日志结构合并树部分，
I think it's a bit, it's overly complicated,
我认为这有点过于复杂，
because it's really about like,
因为它实际上是，
how do you merge these trees based,
如何合并这些树为基础的，
it almost looks like the level compaction,
它看起来像是水平压缩，
but I understand that the like the low level of data structure,
但我理解的是低级别的数据结构，
the key thing I I want you to understand is like,
我想让你们明白的关键一点是，
here's a different approach to storing tuples,
这是一种不同的存储 tuple 的方法，
through these log records,
通过这些日志记录，
and we'll see this idea pop up again,
我们会看到这个想法再次出现，
when we talk about multi version control
当我们讨论多版本控制，
and when we talk about distributed transactions, distributed databases.
当我们讨论分布式事务、分布式数据库时。
This question is,
这个问题是，
why is level compaction preferred over universal compaction,
为什么水平压缩比普遍压实更受欢迎，
I don't know, I don't know if, if it actually is,
我不知道是不是真的，
I don't, I don't think it makes a difference,
我不认为这有什么不同，
and I actually, yeah, and I don't know what the tradeoffs are between the two of them,
事实上，是的，我不知道它们之间的权衡是什么，
other than it's like a,
除了它像是，
I think it sort of like a cleaner architecture in terms of like,
我想它是一种更干净的架构，
I know at this level I'm going to compact
我知道在这个级别，我将压缩，
and it's going to go to this size and go to the next level,
它将达到这个尺寸，并进入下一级别，
whereas in the universal pattern,
然而，在普遍模式中，
you have to have some additional logic side,
你必须有一些额外的逻辑方面，
okay, if I could merge this guy and this guy
如果我可以合并这个和这个，
or this guy and this guy,
或者这个和这个，
which one should I do,
我应该做哪一个，
but I I I don't think,
但是我不认为，
the the RocksDB manual has a lot of good information on the [],
RocksDB 手册中有很多关于[]的信息，
I can post on Piazza if you want afterwards.
如果你想看的话，我可以在之后贴在 Piazza 上。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, so his question is,
所以他的问题是，
what do I mean by period that compaction,
我所说的压缩期是什么意思，
you would have some kind of trigger threshold
你会有某种触发阈值，
or something that says it's time to compact, right,
或者是说是时候压缩了，
it could be, if it's a level compaction, it could be,
如果是水平压缩，它可能是，
okay, I've, I've got three of these guys go ahead and run compaction, right,
我有三个这样的，运行压缩，
or it could be I've done this many of writes, go ahead and compact.
也可能是我做了这么多写入，开始压缩。
And this is so it can be done basically whenever,
这就是说，它可以在任何时候完成，
does not, doesn't it have to be triggered by a read?
它不需要由读取触发吗？
Correct, it, it doesn't have to be triggered by read,
对的，它不需要要由读取触发，
whenever, Yes, yeah.
任何时候，是的。
But it's like, how do this.
但这就像是，这是怎么做的。
It's like, you know, you need to change the oil in your car,
这就像，你需要给你的车换机油，
you can go a long time beyond the, the, you know, the mileage when you're supposed to,
你可以在你应该走的里程之外走很长一段时间，
but it's kind of you shouldn't, right,
但这是你不应该的，
so it's sort of like the best practices,
所以这有点像是最佳实践，
you want to, you know, you want to make sure you set up,
你想确保你准备好了，
do the upkeep that you need to do,
做你需要做的维护，
but of course, if you're running it every second,
但当然，如果你每秒都在运行它，
then that's going to make your reads go slower,
那么这会使你的读取速度变慢，
so it's to balance,
所以，它是如何平衡，
how to figure out, how to, how to, when to do it.
如何弄清楚在什么时候做这件事。
And again, we'll see this,
同样，我们将看到这一点，
when we talk about Postgres and multi version control,
当我们讨论 Postgres 和多版本控制时，
there's this thing called the auto vacuum,
有一种叫自动 vacuum 的东西，
when, when should it run, how should it run,
它应该什么时候运行，它应该如何运行，
it depends on depends on the workload and the hardware.
这取决于工作量和硬件。
Okay.
好的。
So, the two approaches we talked about so far,
所以，我们到目前为止谈到的两种方法，
again, the log-structure storage and the, the sort of the page-oriented storage,
日志结构存储和面向页面存储，
these are tuple-oriented storage,
这是面向 tuple 的存储，
these are, these approaches,
这是方法，
the all going to lie on indexes to find individual tuples,
这一切都依赖索引查找独立的 tuple ，
that are separate from the sort of core storage of the of the tables, the tuple themselves, right,
tuple 本身独立于表的核心存储，
in the tuple-oriented storage,
在面向 tuple 的存储中，
there's these pages, they're unordered,
有这些页面，它们是无序的，
and to get that record ID,
并获取 record ID ，
that gives us the page number and the slot number,
给我们页面编号和 slot 编号，
there's some other magical data structure or index, I said,
还有一些其他神奇的数据结构或索引，
that's going to get us there,
会把我们带到那里，
same thing for the log-structure storage,
日志结构存储也是如此，
we need, we need an index that tells us,
我们需要一个索引告诉我们，
for a given record ID,
对于给定的 record ID ，
where to go find the data that we're looking for, right.
到哪里去查找我们寻找的数据。
And so an alternative approach is that,
所以，另一种方法是，
what if we just keep the tuples automatically sorted,
如果我们只保持 tuple 自动排序，会怎么样，
by just putting it inside the index itself,
只需将其放入索引本身，
and then now you don't have a separate distinct between
现在，你没有单独的区别，
here's the log-structure storage and the index,
这里是日志结构存储和索引，
or here's, here's the slot of pages, and here's the index,
这是是页面插槽和索引，
it's all just indexes.
这些都只是索引。
And so this is what is called index-organized storage or index-organized tables,
这就是所谓的索引组织存储或索引组织表，
and the idea here is that,
这里的想法是，
assuming we have some tree data structure
假设我们有一些树数据结构，
or could be a hash table, for now we'll assume trees,
或者可以是哈希表，现在我们假设是树，
instead of having the the leaf nodes in in the tree with values,
不是让树中的叶节点带有值，
values that provide us the record Id,
值为我们提供 record ID ，
that tells us where to go, find the page that has a data we're looking for,
告诉我们应该去哪里，找到包含我们要查找的数据的页面，
what if the leaf nodes themselves were just the data pages with the tuples,
如果叶子它们自己只是包含 tuple 的数据页面，
so now when I want to do a look up
所以现在当我想要做一个查找，
and say find me key 102,
并且说帮我找到键 102 ，
I follow this index and then [] at the bottom,
我跟随这个索引，然后到达底部，
[] not [], [] at the bottom
达到底部，
and there's the index I'm looking for,
这是我要找的索引，
sorry, there's the data that I'm looking for.
抱歉，这是我要找的数据。
Right?
是吧？
So this sort of idea looks like,
所以这个想法看起来就像，
again, this what this is a rough diagram a B tree,
这是一个粗略的图 B 树，
which cover soon, right,
它很快就会讲到，
there's essentially the inner nodes and then the leaf nodes,
这里有内部节点，然后是叶子节点，
the inner nodes are basically guys [posts] that tell you,
内部节点基本上是告诉你，
for a given key, should I go left or right,
对于给定的键，我应该向左还是向右，
and in the leaf nodes themselves,
而在叶子节点本身，
these will look a lot just like slotted pages,
这些会看起来像插槽页面，
but the difference is that,
但不同的是，
we're going to sort them in, in the actual in the page itself based on the key,
我们将对页面本身基于键进行排序，
and not just a random location in the,
而不仅是随机位置，
based on where we had a free space in the slot array.
基于我们在 slot array 中的空闲空间。
So now again, when I want to do a look up,
所以，现在，当我想要查找，
find me key 102,
帮我查找键 102 ，
I traverse the index,
我遍历索引，
I get to a leaf node, I pop over here,
我到达一个叶节点，在这里弹出，
and then I do binary search on the list of keys,
然后我对键列表进行二分搜索，
and then that'll give me an offset
然后这将给我一个偏移量，
to go find with the data I'm looking for.
查找我要查找的数据。
So this is what is, how, MySQL, when you use the InnoDB engine,
这就是， MySQL ，当你使用 InnoDB 引擎时，
this is, what this what you get for SQLite,
这就是你在 SQLite 中得到的，
this is what you get as well,
这也是你得到的，
I think I said last class,
我想我在上一节课上讲过，
in SQLite, they had this internal primary key called the rowid, right,
在 SQLite 中，他们有一个称为 rowid 的内部主键，
and we can see it through SQL,
我们可以通过 SQL 看到它，
but it's slightly, it's different than the primary key you may define in your in your table itself,
但它与你在表本身中定义的主键略有不同，
because they're using index-oriented storage,
因为它们使用的是索引组织存储，
and then the rowid is is the key,
然后 rowid 是键，
that you do look up something in inside of the, inside of this index.
你在索引里查找一些东西。
So for the real primary, the logical primary key,
所以，对于逻辑主键，
a customer student email address,
客户、学生电子邮件地址，
we would have a separate index,
我们将有一个单独的索引，
that then maps the the email address to the rowid,
然后将电子邮件地址映射到 rowid ，
then you do a look up in the primary key index
然后在主键索引中进行查找，
to get the tuple you're looking for.
以获得你查找的 tuple 。
The question is,
问题是，
it's two key,
它是两个键，
one key for to get to the page and one key inside the page,
一个键用于进入页面，另一个键在页面内，
no, so like if I,
不，如果我，
again, if I'm, if a SQLite, find me rowid equals 1,
如果是 SQLite ，帮我找到 rowid 等于 1 ，
I just traverse this index, the keys are based on rowid,
我只是遍历这个索引，键基于 rowid ，
I land in the page,
我登上了这页，
now I need to find within the page,
现在，我需要在页面中查找，
where rowid 1 is
rowid 1 在哪里，
and I do my lookup on this.
我需要这样查找。
Entire tree is sorted,
整个树都是排序的，
it has to be,
它必须是，
because it's a balanced tree.
因为它是一棵平衡树。
So you get this in SQL Server and, and Oracle,
你可以在 SQL Server 和 Oracle 中获得这个，
but not by default,
但不是在默认情况下，
you have to tell it, I want this,
你得告诉它，我想要这个，
if you use MySQL SQLite, you get this by default,
如果你使用 MySQL SQLite ，默认情况下会得到这个，
I don't think you can turn them off.
我不认为你能关掉它们。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, so his question is,
是的，所以他的问题是，
it's a good point,
这是一个很好的观点，
does this approach still suffer from the things we talked about before,
这种方法是否仍然受到我们之前讨论过的事情的影响，
like fragmentation and and random I/O,
比如碎片化和随机 I/O ，
well, so, for fragmentation, yes, it's unavoidable,
对于碎片化，是的，这是不可避免的，
because in a B+ tree, it needs to be at least half full,
因为在 B+ 树中，它需要至少半满，
so you're going to have a bunch of leaf nodes that are going to be empty,
所以你会有一堆叶节点是空的，
that's unavoidable,
这是不可避免的，
in terms of the random I/O,
就随机 I/O 而言，
if it's updates to random locations in the leaf nodes,
如果是更新到叶节点中的随机位置，
yes, that's unavoidable,
是的，这是不可避免的，
but if you're just inserting, right,
但如果只是插入，
then again, using, using SQLite rowid is an example,
然后，使用 SQLite rowid 是一个例子，
the rowid is just an eternal counter,
rowid 只是一个内部计数器，
for every new tuple, will increment that counter by one,
对于每新的 tuple ，它将递增 1 ，
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 ，
it's monotonically increasing,
它是单调递增的，
so if I just keep inserting to SQLite,
所以如果我继续插入到 SQLite ，
I'm just going to keep appending to this side of the tree
我只是继续追加到树的这一边，
and not touch the other side of the tree,
不会碰树的另一边，
so it's not as bad as doing a much of random I/O,
所以它不会做大量的随机 I/O 那么糟糕，
it's not as good as doing the sequential I/O,
它不如做顺序 I/O 那么好，
you get log-structured,
你从日志结构得到的，
but it's better than it may have in a tuple-oriented storage,
但它比在面向 tuple 存储中的更好，
because at least now the tree is guiding to
因为至少现在树[引导]
only update pages on the side over here,
只更新这边的页面，
so there is some benefit to it.
所以，这是有好处的。
Yes.
是的。
The question is,
问题是，
the rowid is, the rowid is finding a page and key ID is finding a tuple,
rowid 是查找页面， key ID 是查找 tuple 吗，
no, so what I was trying to say,
不，所以我想说的是，
in SQLite, there's the primary key, index,
在 SQLite 中，是主键、索引，
that, that, that stores the the tuples in the leaf nodes,
存储 tuple 在叶节点中，
but instead of whatever the primary key you tell it in your CREATE TABLE statement,
但是，与你在 CREATE TABLE 语句中告诉它的主键不同，
they have an internal rowid is is the primary key,
它们有一个内部 rowid 是主键，
so if you do a look at where email address equals Andy,
所以，如果查看电子邮件地址等于 Andy ，
there's some other index that's going to give you the rowid,
还有一些其他索引将为你提供 rowid ，
and then you use that to traverse the primary key index.
然后你使用它来遍历主键索引。
In in MySQL Innodb,
在 MySQL innodb 中，
they don't do that with a rowid,
他们不使用 rowid ，
it'll be the real primary key to declare in the CREATE TABLE statement,
它将是 CREATE TABLE 语句中声明的真正主键，
that'll be the key you're using here
这将是你在这里使用的键，
and that that's, that's the lookup that you have over here.
这就是你在这里的查找。
Again, and then the pages look like slot architecture,
同样，页面插槽架构，
where the key and the offsets are growing in one direction,
其中键和偏移量在一个方向上增长，
and then the tuple ID, tuples are grown in another direction.
然后 tuple 在另一个方向上增长。
All right, again, so the three major approaches for storing, storing, tuples, sort of within files are going to be
好的，在文件中存储 tuple 的三种主要方法是，
the heap storage with the slotted pages,
堆存储，具有插槽页面，
the log-structure storage with the append and the SSTables, getting rid of disk,
日志结构存储，带有追加和 SSTables ，[避免磁盘]，
and then this index-organized storage.
然后这个索引组织存储。
And there's other one like the ISAMs,
还有其他的，比如 ISAM ，
but these are archaic or they're legacy,
但这些是古老的或它们是遗产，
we don't need to worry about it.
我们不需要担心这个。
All right, so let's talk about now,
好的，那么我们现在谈谈，
once we got, once we have a, once we got to this, we got tuple,
一旦我们有，我们有了 tuple ，
let's talk about what's actually in it now.
现在让我们来谈谈它里面有什么。
So a tuple is just a sequence of bytes,
所以 tuple 是一个字节序列，
and it, it's the job of the database management system,
这是数据库管理系统的工作，
based on the schema that that it's storing in its catalog,
基于存储在目录中的模式，
like when you call CREATE TABLE,
比如当你调用 CREATE TABLE 时，
I I have these attributes of these types,
我有这些类型的属性，
it's the job of the database system
这是数据库系统的工作，
to interpret what those bytes actually are
解释这些字节实际是什么，
and how to, how to do whatever the operation that it is want you want on it, right,
以及如何执行你想要对其执行的任何操作，
if I have two column, column A plus column B,
如果我有两列， A 列加上 B 列，
the database system is gonna know,
数据库系统就会知道，
okay, well column A is a 32 bit integer,
好的， A 列是一个 32 位整数，
column B is a 64 bit integer,
B 列是一个 64 位整数，
therefore I need to do
因此，我需要做，
you know the the the addition operator based on those two types, right.
基于这两种类型的加法运算符。
And so you can sort of think again,
所以你可以再想一想，
just think of it as just a byte buffer, a char array,
只要把它想象成一个字节缓冲区，一个字符数组，
there'll be some header,
有一些 header ，
that says keeps track of maybe the size of it, the null,
来跟踪它的大小，空值，
we'll cover in a second,
我们稍后会讲到，
and then after the header is done,
然后在 header 完成后，
at the first offset, you would have the first column, id column, here
在第一个偏移量，你会有第一个列， id 列，
and then follow, we know the id is an integer,
接下来，我们知道 id 是一个整数，
so that's going to be 32 bits,
所以这将是 32 位，
then after 32 bits, we have the value, which would be 64 bits.
然后，在 32 位之后，我们有 value ，它将是 64 位。
And so internally basically the database system,
所以在数据库系统内部，
if you want to do a C++,
如果你想做 C++ ，
is looking gets the starting location of the of the tuple, right,
是寻找 tuple 的起始位置，
using whatever the slot array method
使用 slot array 方法，
or how we get to jump to that offset in a page,
或者我们如何跳到页面中的那个偏移量，
the header is always going to be the same size for every single tuples,
header 总是与每个 tuple 相同的大小，
we know how to jump past that,
我们知道如何跳过（的 tuple），
and then now we just do a simple arithmetic to say,
现在我们只做一个简单的算术运算，
I know that the, the, the offset of this first column that I'm looking for is
我知道我要寻找的第一列的偏移量是，
this so many bits or bytes after the header,
这个 header 后面的很多位或字节，
or if I want the second column, how to get there,
或者，如果我想要第二列，如何到达那里。
varchar is a little bit complicated,
varchar 有点复杂，
you have to store the length of the field
你必须存储字段的长度，
and that could be in the header, right, or or in line,
该长度可以在 header 中或者在列中，
for now it doesn't matter,
现在并不重要，
but essentially what you're just doing,
但本质上你说做的，
you're just taking some address
你只是在做一些地址，
and you're doing reinterpret cast
你做重新解释转换，
to say the, the system itself should treat that address,
系统本身应该处理那个地址，
that by that address as a 32 bit integer or 64 bit integer or whatever the type is.
通过地址将其作为 32 位整数或 64 位整数或任何类型。
It's the database engine which is doing the interpret?
那是数据库引擎做的解释吗？
Yes, who else would be doing it,
是的，还会有谁来做这件事，
we, we're writing SQL, right,
我们编写 SQL ，
like so SQL, there's no interpret as SQL,
SQL ，这里没有解释 SQL 解释，
this is like the implementation.
这就是实现。
Again, this class is like we're doing this,
这门课就是我们在做这件事，
not the JavaScript programmer.
而不是 JavaScript 程序员。
All right, so someone brought this up last class,
好的，上节课有人提出了这个问题，
which is a good topic,
这是一个很好的话题，
and I want to include it,
我想把它包括进去，
is, one of the things we need to be careful now,
它是，我们现在需要注意的一件事，
as we start storing these bits is dealing with alignment,
当我们开始存储这些比特时，处理对齐，
to make sure that the data we're storing aligns to the,
以确保我们存储的数据对齐，
to how the CPU actually wants to operate on data.
与 CPU 实际想要如何操作数据。
So what I mean this?
那么我说的是什么意思？
The reason I put AndySux is,
我使用 AndySux 原因是，
like people take my slides
人们拿了我的幻灯片，
and they don't know what AndySux means,
他们不知道 AndySux 是什么意思，
so, Google that and you find who who copies it, right.
所以，在 Google 上搜索，你就能找到是谁复制了它。
So, we need to make sure that,
所以，我们需要确保，
all our attributes are aligned to based on the word boundaries of the CPU
我们的所有属性都基于 CPU 的单词边界，
or whatever the architecture we're running on,
或我们运行的任何体系结构来对齐，
to ensure that we don't end up with unexpected behavior,
以确保我们不会出现意外的行为，
when we do operations on this data,
在对这些数据进行操作时，
and that the CPU doesn't have to do extra work.
而且 CPU 不需要做额外的工作。
So let's say I have a table,
假设我有一张表，
I have four columns here,
我这里有四个列，
I have 32 bit integer, a 64 timestamp,
我有 32 位整数， 64 位时间戳，
a 4 byte char and then a zipcode, right.
一个 4 字节字符，然后是一个 zipcode 。
And so assume that we're, we're going to break up our char array,
假设我们要分解我们的 char array ，
representing this tuple into 64 bit words,
把这个 tuple 表示成 64 位字，
cache lines are 64 bytes,
高速缓存行是 64 字节的，
but Postgres lines are based on 64 bits,
但是 Postgres 行是基于 64 位的，
or I don't know what SQLite does,
我不知道 SQLite 做的，
but they're all doing some variation of this, right.
但他们都在做一些这个的变体。
So the first thing I'm going to do is,
所以我要做的第一件事是，
we have, for id columm, that's 32 bits,
我们有，对于 id 列，那是 32 位，
we store that there,
我们把它存储在那里，
then we have this date timestamp, the creation date, that 64 bits,
然后我们有这个 date 时间戳，创建日期，它是 64 位，
so we store that right after that
所以我们在那之后存储它，
and so forth, with the other ones, right.
以此类推，还有其他的。
And so again, now when I want to do a lookup in, in my system
所以，现在当我想在系统中进行查找时，
to do, do some operation on this byte array that I've gotten for this tuple,
对我为这个 tuple 获得的数组进行一些操作，
say on the customer date, the creation date,
比如客户日期，创建日期，
the problem with this is that,
这样做的问题在于，
that attribute is going to span two words, right,
那个属性将跨越两个字，
because this each word is 64 bits,
因为每个字都是 64 位，
the first id field was 32 bits,
第一个 id 字段为 32 位，
so this 64 bits spans two consecutive words.
所以这个 64 位跨越两个连续的字。
Anybody know what happens when you do this in a CPU,
有人知道当你在 CPU 中这样做的时候，会发生什么吗，
when you try to jump to a memory address
当你试图跳到一个内存地址，
and do some operational on something that spans the word boundaries,
并对一些跨越字边界的东西进行操作时，
what does x86 do?
x86 是怎么做的？
So x86, Intel likes to make your life easy
所以 x86 ， Intel 喜欢让你的生活变得轻松，
and not have to worry about these things,
而不必担心这些事情，
so they'll do the extra reads for you, right,
所以他们会为你做额外的读取，
they want to hide it,
他们想把它隐藏起来，
they want to hide all, all the the complexities of the architecture,
他们想要隐藏架构的所有的复杂性，
so they'll do extra work,
所以他们会做额外的工作，
but now this is going to make your database system run slower,
但现在这会使你的数据库系统运行较慢，
because what should have been,
因为这本来应该是，
you know, one one register read or one cache line read
一个寄存器读取或一个高速缓存行读取，
to go fetch something into a CPU register,
去获取一些东西到 CPU 寄存器中，
now is going to be two cache line reads,
现在会是两个高速缓存行读取，
but again, there's no error,
但是，这是没有错误的，
it just Intel takes care of it for you.
这只是 Intel 帮你处理的。
But not every system, not every architecture would do that,
但并不是每个系统、每个架构都会这样做，
previously before in ARM,
以前，在 ARM 之中，
they would give you, they would reject it,
他们会拒绝它，
they would recognize that you're trying to do a misalign operation
它们会识别出你正在尝试执行未对齐的操作，
and then throw an error, hoping you would catch it,
然后抛出一个错误，希望您能捕捉到，
now, in the newer versions, I think ARM 7,
现在，在较新的版本中，我认为是 ARM 7 ，
they, they handle it now like Intel does,
他们现在处理像 Intel 一样，
but there's, it's just slower.
但是，它只是慢了一点。
This is rare, but what could happen is that,
这很罕见，但可能发生的情况是，
it it'll do the reads for you,
它将为你进行读取，
but it is no guarantee that the bits are going to land in the right order.
但不能保证位将以正确的顺序到达。
So going back here,
所以回到这里，
I have to do two reads to get this word and this word
我必须进行两次读取，才能得到这个字和这个字，
to put together the date attribute,
从而将 date 属性组合在一起，
it may put the last bits in front of the other ones,
它可能会把后面的位放在另一个的前面，
seems like a terrible idea,
这似乎是个糟糕的主意，
but the older CPUs would do that.
但老式的 CPU 会这么做。
Of course, that means now your program kind of random errors
当然，这意味着现在你的程序出现一种随机错误，
and, and, and messed up data
而且搞砸了数据，
and people are going to notice and complain,
人们会注意到并抱怨，
and that's bad.
这是不好的。
Again, that's part of the reason why Intel tries to hide that from you,
这也是 Intel 试图对你隐瞒这一点的部分原因，
even though it makes your thing run slower.
尽管它会让你的东西运行得更慢。
So we need to make sure that,
所以我们需要确保，
none of the attributes in our tuple,
我们的 tuple 没有任何属性，
in our, essentially in our byte array,
在我们的字节数组中，
because again, now we're talking about things, we brought into memory,
因为现在，我们讨论的是带入内存的东西，
that none of them are going to span these boundaries.
它们中没有一个会跨越这些界限。
So the two approaches to handle this are padding or reordering.
所以，处理这个问题的两种方法是填充或重新排序。
So with, with padding, the basic idea is,
所以，对于填充，基本的想法是，
to recognize that,
意识到，
if I'm breaking up to 64 bit words
如果我要拆分 64 位字，
as I add my attributes as going across,
当我添加属性跨越时，
if I recognize that the next attribute doesn't fit within my single word,
如果我意识到下一个属性不适合我的单个字，
then I'll just put a bunch of zeros there and pad that,
然后我只需要在那里放一堆零，把它填满，
and then internally, the bookkeeping of the system
然后在内部，系统的[记录]，
as when it, when it's interpreting these bytes,
当它解释这些字节时，
it knows that, okay, I need this id here,
它知道，好的，我需要这个 id ，
and then the date attribute, that's going to be the next word,
然后是 date 属性，这将是下一个字，
so just ignore these 32 bits there.
所以忽略这 32 位就行了。
The other approach is do reordering.
另一种方法是重新排序。
I don't think any, most systems don't do this automatically,
我不认为，大多数系统不会自动完成这项工作，
Some of the academic systems we built, one that did this, do this automatically,
我们建立的一些学术系统，会自动完成这个，
but most systems will lay out the bits exactly where you tell it
但大多数系统会准确地列出你说的内容，
and then put padding in to make it better.
然后添加填充物，以使其更好。
So the idea here is that,
所以这里的想法是，
if I the logical view of the, of the table,
如果我看到表的逻辑视图，
whatever defined in the CREATE TABLE statement,
不管 CREATE TABLE 语句定义了什么，
I'll tell you if things are sorted in this order,
我会告诉你东西按这个顺序排序，
but underneath the covers, I'll just move things around,
但在幕后，我会移动东西，
so I can pack things in better
这样我就可以更好地打包东西，
and then, if necessary, I'll add bits at the end like that.
然后，如果需要，我会在末尾添加一些像这样的位。
Yes.
是的。
This question is, how do varchar handle this case?
这个问题是， varchar 如何处理这种情况的？
Yeah, for padding.
是的，对于填充。
That's what I'm saying,
这就是我说的，
so, in the systems that do automatic reordering,
所以，在执行自动重新排序的系统中，
you don't store the varchar in line,
你不会将 varchar 存储在一行，
unless less, unless they're 64 bits or less,
除非它们是 64 位或更少，
and instead, you store a pointer to some other location,
取而代之的是，你存储一个指向其他位置的指针，
that we'll see in a second,
我们稍后会看到，
these external, these oversized attribute tables or pages that are sort of separately,
这些外部的，这些超大的属性表或页面是分开的，
so you can do this reordering
所以，你可以进行这种重新排序，
and not worry about variable length things.
而不必担心可变长度的事情。
Question, do I need this last this thing here,
问题是，我需要最后这个东西吗，
do I need this,
我需要这个吗，
no.
不。
So we can see this in Postgres,
所以，我们可以在 Postgres 中看到这个，
so Postgres will not do automatic reordering,
Postgres 不会进行自动重新排序，
but it will do padding,
但会进行填充，
and there some simple things we can see about,
我们可以看到一些简单的事情，
if we, when we reorder the,
如果我们重新排序，
when, when we reorder, reorder the CREATE TABLE savings or reorder tuples,
当我们重新排序 CREATE TABLE 保存的东西或重新排序 tuple 时，
that we can store things in less space.
我们可以在更小的空间内存储东西。
So.
所以。
So just more Postgres syntax here,
所以这里是更多的 Postgres 语法，
but Postgres has this nice little function called row,
Postgres 有一个很好的小函数，叫做 row ，
and essentially it just takes the comma separated list of values you give it,
本质上它只接受你给它的逗号分隔的值列表，
it makes a row, right,
它会做一个行，
and then we can cast it,
然后我们可以对它转码，
now we can add this :: thing at the end of all our values
现在我们可以在所有值的末尾加上 :: 的东西，
and that, that basically casting the value to a given type,
这基本上是将值转换为给定的类型，
so I can do a small int, a regular int and a big int,
所以我可以做一个小整数，一个常规整数和一个大整数，
so a two byte int, four byte int or eight byte int, right.
所以是两个字节的整型，四个字节的整型，或者八个字节的整型。
So now Postgres has a nice little function called pg_column_size,
现在 Postgres 有一个很好的小函数，名为 pg_column_size ，
that'll tell you the size of this record, this tuple in bytes.
它会告诉你这个记录、这个 tuple 的大小，以字节为单位。
So in this case here,
所以在这个例子中，
it's tell me the size of this row I created, for bytes,
它告诉我创建的行的大小，以字节为单位，
if I go back to my previous one,
如果我返回到前一个，
and run that.
并运行。
Yeah.
是的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Go back to the row had before,
回到以前的那个行，
without casting to types,
没有进行类型转换，
told me it's 36, right,
告诉我是 36 ，
which makes sense,
这说得通，
because, this last one here,
因为，这里最后一个，
I was making that 64 bit integer,
我把它转换成 64 位整数，
or Postgres in this case here,
或者在这里是 Postgres ，
it's storing it as all eight bytes,
它将其存储为 8 字节，
four bit, four byte integers, 32 bit integers,
4 字节的整数和 32 位的整数，
and then a little extra space for padding.
然后有一些额外的空间用于填充。
So we can see this now,
所以我们现在可以看到，
if we take a,
如果我们取一个，
let me do it first without the size,
让我先做一下，不要大小，
so let's make a row,
所以，让我们来创建一个行，
that has some chars, and then two byte, four byte and eight byte integers,
它有一些字符，然后是两个字节、四个字节和八个字节的整数，
but I'm intermixing the chars with the the integers, right,
但我把字符和整数混在一起了，
so now if I say,
所以现在如果我说，
I guess, Postgres, what is the size of this, I get 48 bytes,
我想， Postgres ，这个有多大，我得到 48 字节，
but if I redo it, where I put all the integers first,
但如果我把所有的整数放在第一位，
basically reordering as I was shown before,
重新排序，就像我之前展示的那样，
and then put the chars all at the end,
然后把所有的字符都放在最后，
now I get down to 44 bytes,
现在我只剩下 44 字节，
because Postgres has to pad things out
因为 Postgres 必须填充内容，
to make sure that everything is 64 bit aligned.
以确保所有内容都是 64 位对齐的。
But it doesn't do do this for you automatically,
但它不会自动为你做到这一点，
you have to do it,
你必须这么做，
you have to tell Postgres I want this,
你必须告诉 Postgres 我想要这个，
again, where there's some systems that can do this for you automatically.
再说一次，有一些系统可以自动为你做这件事。
Makes sense?
能理解吗？
Again, I like this,
同样，我喜欢这个，
because we can just do SQL commands,
因为我们可以只执行 SQL 命令，
we can get a,
我们可以得到一个，
we can get a view to slightly to the internals of the storage manager of a database system
我们可以稍微了解一下数据库系统存储管理器的内部结构，
to say how it actually laying things up.
以了解它实际是如何放置的。
Okay?
好的？
All right, so now let's talk about,
好的，现在让我们来讨论一下，
we talk about integers,
我们讨论了整数，
we talk about the varchar a little bit,
我们稍微讨论了一点 varchar ，
let's talk about the other, sort of the core SQL data types
让我们讨论一个其他核心的 SQL 数据类型，
and how the database system is actually going, going to represent them.
以及数据库系统是如何表示它们的。
So for all INTEGER data types,
所以对于所有的整型数据类型，
these are essentially going to be the same thing
它们本质上是（与 C++ 中）相同的，
as you get when you allocate a variable of integer type, a large int, whatever in in C++,
当你在 C++ 中分配一个整型变量，一个大整型，不管什么，
it's gonna be the same representation,
它将是相同的表示，
because that's what the hardware supports,
因为这是硬件所支持的，
the hardware is going to have,
硬件将会有，
there, there's a standard, that representation,
这里有一个标准，表示，
for whatever two's complement integer is either signed or unsigned,
对于任何 2 的补码整数是有符号的还是无符号的，
whatever you get in C++, that follows the standard
无论你在 C++ 中得到什么，都遵循标准，
and that's what the hardware supports
这就是硬件支持的，
and that's what you get in SQL, right.
这就是你在 SQL 中得到的。
For floating points or or floating point numbers or fixed point numbers,
对于浮点数或定点数，
there'll be floating point or REAL numbers,
会有浮点数或实数，
and again that's defined in the IEEE-754 standard,
这也是在 IEEE-754 标准中定义的，
it specifies how hardware should represent these, these decimal numbers,
它规定了硬件应该如何表示这些小数，
but every database system is also going to have what are called fixed-point decimals, so NUMERIC or DECIMAL,
但每个数据库系统也有所谓的定点小数，即 NUMERIC 或 DECIMAL 。
where each of those implementations are going to be different per system
这些实现在每个系统中都是不同的，
and we can see the performance difference of the two approaches in a second.
我们可以稍后会看到这两种方法的性能差异。
For VARCHAR, VARBINARY TEXT and BLOBs,
对于 VARCHAR VARBINARY TEXT 和 BLOB ，
these are typically gonna be stored as something with a header
这些通常存储为带有 header 的东西，
that tells you the length of it,
header 会告诉你它的长度，
followed by the bytes of the of the actual value,
后跟实际值的字节，
or if it's too big to be stored in line in the tuple itself, within within a page,
或者如果它太大而无法存储在页面内的 tuple 本身中，
there'll be a pointer to some other page that has the data that you need for this attribute,
这里会有一个指针指向包含这个属性所需数据的其他页面，
so as I said, for for in-memory system,
如我所说的，对于内存中系统，
if it's less than 64 bits,
如果它少于 64 位，
they'll store it in line,
他们会将其存储在行中，
if it's not, then they store a pointer,
如果不是，他们将存储一个指针，
in the different, in in a disk-based database system,
在基于磁盘的数据库系统中，
it's going to depend on the implementation,
这将取决于实现情况，
and we see again, we see that in a second.
我们将在稍后看到。
For TIMESTAMPs, DATEs, and INTERVALs and so forth,
对于时间戳、日期和间隔等，
these are going to be typically 32 or 64 bit integers,
这些通常是 32 位或 64 位整数，
that's just the number of milliseconds or microseconds since the Unix epoch, January 1st, 1970,
这只是从 Unix 纪元（1970年1月1日）以来的毫秒数或微秒数，
and if you want to store this with, with with timestamp information,
如果你想要使用时间戳信息来存储它，
typically they store it as the based on UTC timestamp, right, GMT 0,
通常他们会基于 UTC 时间戳（GMT 0）来存储，
and then they store additional metadata,
然后他们存储额外的元数据，
say what timestamp are you in,
比如你所在的时间戳，
and they can convert it as needed,
他们可以根据需要进行转换，
and the system handles that for you.
系统会为你处理这一点。
So because for these these types up here, the INTEGER types,
所以对于上面这些类型，整数类型，
because we're relying on the hardware to store, whatever,
因为我们依赖硬件来存储，
store the data, how the hardware wants to represent it,
存储数据，以硬件想要如何表示它的方式，
that typically means you just can't copy the files,
这通常意味着你不能复制文件，
like the raw database files that you generate
比如你生成的原始数据库文件，
from one architecture to another,
从一个架构到另一个架构，
like if it's big-endian or or little-endian,
比如，如果它是大端模式或小端模式，
like x86 is little-endian, Power and ARM are big-endian,
比如 x86 是小端模式， Power 和 ARM 是大端模式，
like you can't take the binary files from database and put it to another one,
你不能从数据库中提取二进制文件并将其放到另一个，
because they're gonna, you know, the bits are gonna be flipped and it'll get messed up.
因为位会被翻转，它会被搞乱。
SQLite avoid this problem,
SQLite 避免了这个问题，
where, because they store everything as actually varchars,
因为他们把所有东西都存储为 varchar 。
and at runtime, they cast things based on the type in the attribute,
在运行时，它们根据属性中的类型进行转换，
because then they get that portability guarantee,
因为这样他们就能得到可移植性的保证，
that no matter where you know what, where you pop the file in,
无论你把文件放在哪里，
they'll always have it in in the, in the right order.
他们总是会有正确的顺序。
So spend a little time talking about FLOATs and REALs and NUMERICs
所以，花一点时间讨论一下浮点数、实数和小数，
and again, this will be a good example
这是一个很好的例子，
of where the database systems are going to do something different
说明数据库系统将在哪里做一些不同的事情，
and the, you can't just rely on the hardware to do do certain things for you,
你不能仅仅依靠硬件来为你做某些事情，
because we care about correctness of data
因为我们关心数据的正确性，
and the hardware can't guarantee that for us.
而硬件不能为我们保证这一点。
All right, so for VARIABLE PRECISION NUMBERS, right,
好的，所以对于可变精度数字，
just like before in integers,
就像以前的整数一样，
we're going to rely on C++ implementation for this, right,
我们将依赖于 C++ 实现，
so if you call float, real or double in SQL,
所以如果你在 SQL 中调用浮点、实数或双精度数，
you'll, you'll get the same float or double you would get in C++,
你会得到和 C++ 一样的浮点数或双精度数，
so typically these are going to be faster than the fixed-point numbers,
通常情况下，这些会比定点数快，
we'll see in a second,
我们一会儿就会看到，
because the hardware can natively support this.
因为硬件本身就能支持这个。
But the problem is, though,
但问题是，
they're not going to have,
他们不会有，
they can't guarantee the correctness of values,
它们不能保证数值的正确性，
when you start doing larger calculations,
当你开始进行更大的计算时，
because of rounding issues,
因为四舍五入问题，
because you can't store exactly decimals in hardware.
因为你不能在硬件中存储准确的小数。
So everyone's probably seen,
所以每个人都可能见过，
you know, a simple test program like this,
像这样一个简单的测试程序，
when you first learn C or C++,
当你第一次学习 C 或 C++ 时，
I have two floating point numbers, 32 bit floating point numbers,
我有两个浮点数， 32 位浮点数，
I want to sort 0.1 and 0.2
我有 0.1 和 0.2 ，
and then I just want to add them together and see what the output is,
然后我将它们相加，看看输出是什么，
so in the first version,
所以在第一个版本中，
I'll just call printf to dump out the x+y, like that,
我只是调用 printf 来计算 x+y ，
and I would, I would get something that should look at 0.3, right,
我会得到一个应该是 0.3 的值，
and when I run that, I actually get that, that looks, that looks okay,
当我运行它的时候，它看起来是好的，
but in actuality, if I increase the number of digits,
但是实际上，如果我增加位数，
I'm going to write out in my printf statement,
在我的 printf 语句中输出的（位数），
now I end up with something that looks like this, right.
现在我得到的东西看起来像这样。
Because again, the hardware can't represent 0.3 exactly,
因为，硬件并不能准确地表示 0.3 ，
it's going to be some approximation based on that.
它会在此基础上有一些近似值。
So, okay, if I'm doing, you know, a simple program like before,
所以，好的，如果我做一个简单的程序，像之前一样，
where I was just doing x+y
我只做 x+y ，
and I print that out to a human,
然后我把它打印出来给一个人，
yeah, sure, maybe that's not a big deal, right,
是的，当然，也许这没什么大不了的，
but if I'm doing, you know, complex calculations,
但如果我在做复杂的计算，
because I'm trying to land something on the moon
因为我想在月球上着陆，
or, you know, put a satellite space
或者把卫星放到太空，
or if it's your bank account and you're doing interest calculations,
或者如果这是你的银行账户，你在计算利息，
then this rounding error is actually going to matter
那么这个舍入误差实际上很重要，
and people are going to notice and complain.
人们会注意到并抱怨。
So for this reason, database systems are also going to provide these fixed precision numbers of fixed-point decimals,
所以，数据库系统也将提供这些固定精度的定点小数，
where the database systems is going to do bunch of extra work
数据库系统将做更多额外的工作，
to make sure that you don't have these rounding errors,
以确保你不会有这些舍入误差，
you can get this in Java with BigDecimal,
你可以在 Java 中使用 BigDecimal 获得这个，
you can get this in python, I think, with Decimal type as well, right,
你可以在 Python 中使用 Decimal 得到它，
they're all, basically all the different systems are going to do something slightly different,
基本上所有不同的系统都会做一些略有不同的事情，
but at a high level,
但在更高的级别上，
essentially, they're going to store a,
从本质上讲，它们将存储一个，
very like representatio of the number you're trying to trying to represent,
非常类似于你试图表示的数字的表示，
and then additional metadata tell you where the decimal point is
然后，附加的元数据会告诉你小数点的位置，
or whether it's signed or unsigned
或者它是有符号的还是无符号的，
or is it negative
或者是否是负数，
and or not a number and so forth.
或者不是数字等等。
Again, we have to do this extra work,
我们必须做这项额外的工作，
because the hardware can't guarantee this for us.
因为硬件不能为我们保证这个。
So here's what Postgres does,
所以，这是 Postgres 所做的，
so this is the numeric type in Postgres,
这是 Postgres 中的 numeric 类型，
this is actually from the source code itself,
这实际上来自源代码本身，
and you can see that,
你可以看到，
they're going to represent the type of numeric as some kind of struct
它们将把数字的类型表示为某种结构，
with a bunch of additional metadata about what the number actually is,
带有一堆关于数字实际是什么的附加元数据，
but the core thing they're storing internally along with this metadata,
但他们内部存储的核心内容与元数据一起，
here's how to store the actual number itself,
这里是如何存储实际数字本身，
is this NumericDigit array here,
是这里这个 NumericDigit 数组，
well, that's just a type cast to an unsigned char up above,
这只是上面一个无符号字符的类型转换，
so they're literally storing your decimal as a string value,
所以他们真的在存储你的小数作为字符串值，
and then they use this metadata to figure out,
然后他们使用这些元数据来找出，
you know how to interpret that string to put it to be the correct form.
如何将这个字符串解释为正确的形式。
So again, the hardware doesn't know anything about this,
再说一次，硬件对此一无所知，
this is what the database system has implemented,
这是数据库系统实现的，
so we can't just do x+y, we can in C++,
所以我们不能只做 x+y ，在 C++ 中，
we got to do more complicated arithmetic,
我们必须做更复杂的算术，
where you want to start calculating or you know, using these numeric types in, in, in queries.
你想要开始计算，或者在查询中使用这些数字类型，
So this is just a, a brief snippet of the, the addition function for two numeric in Postgres,
所以，这是两个 Postgres 中 numeric 的加法函数的一个简短片段，
and as you can see,
正如你所看到的，
there's a bunch of checks for that struct
对于这个结构，有一堆检查，
or to see whether it's zero or negative or signed or whatever,
看它是零还是负的，或者是有符号的，或者别的什么，
this just adds two numbers together,
这只是将两个数字相加，
this is obviously way more expensive than calling a single instruction in the CPU x+y,
这显然比在 CPU 中调用单个指令 x+y 要昂贵得多，
I don't want to get the impression I'm, I'm, I'm shaming Postgres,
我不想让人觉得我在羞辱 Postgres ，
MySQL has the same issue, right,
MySQL 也有同样的问题，
they're doing the same thing,
他们在做同样的事情，
they're going to store their, set their digit as a varchar,
他们会把他们的，将他们的数字设置为 varchar ，
that can store it as a 32 bit integer,
可以将其存储为 32 位整数，
but again, they have additional metadata to keep track of what the numeric type actually is
但同样，他们有额外的元数据来跟踪实际的 numeric 类型，
and just like Postgres, they're going to have,
就像 Postgres ，他们有，
their own implementations of doing additional checks.
他们自己的实现做额外检查。
It's not sexy, but you know you do need it,
这并不性感，但你确实需要它，
so in the sake of time,
所以，为了节省时间，
if we have time in the end,
如果我们最后有时间，
we can do a demo to show you the performance difference,
最后我们可以做一个 demo 向你展示性能差异，
but it's about 2x, right,
但这是大约是 2x ，
the, the numeric versions or the database implemented versions of these decimals,
数据库实现的这些 decimal 的版本，
it would be about 2x lower than the, than the hardware versions.
它将大约比硬件版本慢 2x 倍。
All right, for nulls, the the most common way to do this is that,
好的，对于空值，最常见的方法是，
for every single tuple,
对于每一个 tuple ，
in that header will be a bitmap,
在 header 中都会有一个位图，
that keeps track of which attributes that are set the null for that given tuple, right,
跟踪给定的 tuple 的哪些属性被设置为空值，
and again, the header, the size of this bitmap will vary based on the number of attributes you have,
同样， header 这个位图的大小将根据你拥有的属性的数量而变化，
which we know whether it could be null or not,
我们知道它是否可能为空，
because it's in the CREATE TABLE statement, right,
因为它在 CREATE TABLE 语句中，
again, the advantage of using a schema instead of storing Json whatever in there,
使用模式而不是存储 Json 在那里的优点，
we have a schema,
我们有一个模式，
we we know whether a column has been been defined as not null or not,
我们知道一个列是否被定义为非空，
and therefore if if it, if it has been declared as not null,
因此，如果它被声明为非空，
we don't need to store this bitmap
我们不需要存储这个位图，
or you don't store entry for it.
或者你不存储它的条目。
So this is the most common approach,
所以这是最常见的方法，
now, does mean there's some overhead here,
这确实意味着有一些开销，
for every single tuple now,
对于每个单独的 tuple ，
in the header, we got to have this bitmap.
在 header 中，我们都必须有这个位图。
Less common, but another approach to do this would be
不太常见，但另一种方法是，
to have special values,
设置特殊的值，
where you basically say there's some value within the range of values I could have for each type,
你可以说在每种类型的值范围内有一些值，
that if I had that value,
如果我有那个值，
then I'll assume that that it's, it's, it's a null.
那么我会假设它是空值。
So if I want to know whether a 32 bit integer is, is null,
所以如果我想知道一个 32 位的整数是不是空值，
then I'll say the 32 bit min number, I could have, negative whatever it is,
我会说 32 位的最小值可以有的是，不管是什么负值，
if my value is that, then I'll treat that as null.
如果我的值是那个，那么我会认为它是空值。
So it's one less value I could potentially store,
所以它少了一个我可以潜在存储的价值，
and now there's a bunch of extra stuff
现在有一堆额外的事情，
I have to do in the rest of my system
我必须在我的系统的其余部分中做，
to keep track of, okay, if I'm looking at a 32 bit integer,
来跟踪，好的，如果我看的是 32 位整数，
if it is that min value that I know it's null
如果它是最小值，我知道它是空值，
and not let people insert it arbitrarily.
不让人们随意插入它。
The worst choice,
最糟糕的选择，
and I don't have, I don't have a screenshot,
我没有截图，
the worst choice I've only seen one system ever actually do is
我所见过的只有一个系统做的最糟糕的选择是，
for every single tuple itself,
对于每个单独的 tuple ，
sorry, every single attribute in the tuple,
抱歉， tuple 中的每个单独的属性，
you have a little flag in front of it, tells you whether it's null or not,
在它前面都有一个小的标志，告诉你它是否为空，
and the reason why this is terrible is,
这很糟糕的原因是，
because when we talk about alignment, right,
当我们谈到对齐时，
I can't have a, you know, I can't have a 32 bit integer and put one bit in front of it,
我不能有一个 32 位的整数，然后在它前面放一位，
to say, hey, this thing's null or not,
来表示，这个东西是不是空的，
I gotta store another byte,
我必须存储另一个字节，
so now all my 32 bit integers
所以现在我所有的 32 位整数，
and if I want to be 64 bit line,
如果我想成为 64 位的行，
maybe got to store the double size,
可能必须存储双倍大小，
so to store 32 bit integer, to keep track with this null,
所以为了存储 32 位整数，为了跟踪这个空值，
if I'm putting this flag in front of it
如果我把这个标志放在它前面，
and they have to store another 32 bits,
他们必须存储另外 32 位，
just to have one bit to say that it's null or not.
只需要有一位来判断它是否为空值。
Do I have a screenshot here, let me see,
我有截图吗，让我看看，
the only system that I know that actually did this was MemSQL,
我所知道的唯一做这个的系统是 MemSQL ，
which is the earlier name of, of, of SingleStore,
它是 SingleStore 的早期名称，
so despite them, you know, sponsoring the class,
尽管他们赞助了课程，
I don't, I don't have the screenshot here,
我没有截图在这里，
I'll put on Slack,
我会放在 Slack 上，
that was the shittiest idea, it's one of the shittiest ideas, I've ever seen,
这是我见过的最烂的想法之一，
but they got rid of it,
但他们去掉了它，
because it's super wasteful
因为它非常浪费，
and they do the column header now.
他们现在做了列 header。
For large values, like really large values, variable length values,
对于非常大的值，可变长度的值，
those database systems are not going to let you store them directly in the page itself, right,
这些数据库系统不会让你直接将它们存储在页面本身中，
again, a page size is the is defined by the database system
同样，页面大小是由数据库系统定义的，
and every single page within that. That table has to have the same page size, right,
表中的每一页必须具有相同的页面大小，
there's an experiment system at Germany,
在德国有一个实验系统，
that they can support variable length pages,
他们可以支持可变长度的页面，
we can ignore that, nobody else does that,
我们可以忽略这个，其他人都不会这么做，
but so that means that like,
但这意味着，
at some point I have to decide,
在某个时刻，我需要决定，
should I store this large varchar, large string in, in my, my tuple page or not,
我是否应该在我的 tuple 页面中存储这个很大的 varchar 字符串，
and so for this,
对于这个，
if it exceeds,
如果它超过了，
for everything, they're going to have different thresholds to say,
对于所有东西，他们将有不同的门槛，
when can you not store it,
什么时候不能存放它，
and we need to put it into what is called an overflow page.
我们需要把它放到所谓的溢出页面中。
So in Postgres, they call it the TOAST,
在 Postgres 中，他们称之为 TOAST ，
I forget what it actually stands for,
我忘了它实际上代表的是什么，
but any attribute that's larger than 2 kilobytes,
但任何大于 2 千字节的属性，
they'll store it as a separate page,
它们都会将其存储为单独的页面，
and then in the actual tuple itself,
然后在实际的 tuple 本身中，
they'll just have a pointer or a record ID and an offset,
它们将只有一个指针或一个 record ID 和一个偏移量，
that then points to where to go find the actual value, that you're looking for right.
然后指向要查找的实际值的位置。
And again, you as the sql programmer,
你作为 SQL 程序员，
you don't know this, you don't care,
你不知道这个，也不关心，
you call a SELECT * on the query
你在查询上调用 SELECT * ，
and the database system is responsible for going reading the the base tuple,
数据库系统负责读取基础 tuple ，
recognizing that it's pointing to an overflow page,
识别出它指向溢出页面，
go get that data and then copy it into the buffer,
去获取数据，然后将其复制到缓冲区中，
that then produces the output for you.
然后为你生成输出。
So it hides underneath the covers, that it actually done this for you.
所以它隐藏在下面，为你做了这个。
All right, so Postgres is, is 2 kilobytes,
好的，所以 Postgres 是 2 千字节，
they have up to 8 kilobytes,
它们最多 8 千字节，
I think you can tune this,
我认为你可以调整这个，
but it goes up to obviously you can't exceed 8 kilobytes.
但很明显，你不能超过 8 千字节。
In MySQL, the overflow size is one half the current page size.
在 MySQL 中，溢出大小是当前页面大小的一半。
And then in SQL Server,
然后在 SQL Server 中，
surprisingly, you can set the,
意外地，你可以设置，
the default is if it exceeds the size of the page, then it overflows.
默认是，如果它超过页面大小，它将溢出，
So the the size of the data trying to store
所以，尝试存储的数据大小，
in this oversized attribute plus the regular data,
这个超大属性中的数据加上常规数据，
the combination of that exceeds the size of a page,
这个组合超过页面的大小，
then put the oversized data to another page, right,
把超大的数据放到另一个页面，
and you can chain these things together,
你可以把这些东西链在一起，
so say you want to store for whatever reason, a one gigabyte video or ten gigabyte video,
假设你出于任何原因，想要存储 1G 或10G的视频，
your database system couldn't let you do that,
你的数据库系统不允许你这样做，
and then this overflow page,
然后这个溢出页面，
since they all have to be the same fixed length size as well,
因为它们都必须是相同的固定长度大小，
it could just have a pointer to say,
它可以有一个指针来说，
okay, here's the data for this range of the data for this attribute,
好的，这是这个属性的数据范围的数据，
but, oh, by the way, here's a pointer to the next page
但是，顺便说一句，这里有一个指向下一页的指针，
and you got to follow along that linked list,
你必须沿着该链表，
go get all the data and put it back together.
去拿所有的数据，然后把它们放在一起。
So the last thing you can do is called external file storage, external value storage,
你可以做的最后一件事称为外部值存储，
and this is where,
这就是，
the database system is not going to store the the large data,
数据库系统不会存储大数据，
the large attribute in pages that it manages,
它管理的页面中的大属性，
it's going to write it out to your local file system
它会将其写出到你的本地文件系统，
and then internally store the URI or the URL of where that data is located,
然后在内部存储该数据所在位置的 URI 或 URL ，
so that when you query against the table
所以，当你对表进行查询，
and you go get that attribute,
并获取该属性时，
it goes to the OS and get that, that that data
它会转到操作系统并获取数据，
copies it into its buffer and then hands it back to you.
将其复制到缓冲区中，然后将交回给你。
So in I think only Postgres, Oracle and MySQL, Oracle and SQL Server can do this,
我认为只有 Oracle 和 SQL Server 能做到这个，
in Oracle, they called BFILEs,
在 Oracle 中，他们称为 BFILE ，
in Microsoft are called FILESTREAMs,
在 Microsoft 中，被称为 FILESTREAM ，
and again it's just a URI to some data on on disk
它只是磁盘上一些数据的 URI ，
and it does the syscall to go get it from the, from the operating system.
它执行系统调用从操作系统获取它。
In Postgres, you can do this for,
在 Postgres 中，你可以做这个，
they call it Foreign Data Wrappers,
它们称为外部数据包装器，
there's, there's additional mechanisms to store data and [cloud] storage,
这是额外的机制来存储数据和云存储，
and then again, now within a single SQL interface,
然后，现在在单个 SQL 界面中，
I can go fetch the data
我可以获取数据，
and have appear as if it was in the the table itself.
并使其看起来就像在表本身中一样。
So when we write things out to these external files,
所以，当我们将内容写入这些外部文件时，
the database system cannot, cannot make any changes to it, right,
数据系统不能对其进行任何更改，
it's, it's like you've written out to the file system,
就像你写到了文件系统一样，
I'm not going to go and make in place updates to it,
我不会去做原地更新，
I can't update it,
我无法更新它，
I can only read it in
我只能读入它，
and then if I delete the, if I delete the tuple, that thing, that's pointing to this file,
如果我删除指向这个文件的 tuple ，
there's mechanisms decide, do I also want to delete the file as well.
这里有机制决定，我是否也想删除该文件。
And so the reason why, why this you may want to do this is,
所以，可能这样做的原因是，
because, as I said,
因为，正如我所说的，
you don't want to store like a 10 gigabyte file in your database system,
你不想在数据库系统中存储 10GB 的文件，
for, for management reasons,
出于管理原因，
because then it's a log record that becomes expensive,
因为日志记录变得昂贵，
but also too typically, database management systems are stored on higher end hardware,
但通常情况下，数据库管理系统存储在更高端的硬件上，
and that makes storage expensive,
这会使存储空间变得昂贵，
if you use Amazon RDS,
如果你使用亚马逊 RDS ，
I think they charge 4x more for storage than you get from EBS
我想他们会多收比 EBS 贵 4 倍的存储费用，
and certainly EBS is even more, if you have a locally attached attached disk,
当然 EBS 比你有一个本地连接的磁盘更高，
so you don't want to be storing these large files
所以，你不希望存储这些大文件，
and maybe your own readonly directly in the in the data that's managed by,
也不希望你的[只读]存储直接被管理，
the the the files that are managed by the database system,
文件被数据库系统管理，
let the OS on some cheaper storage handle that for you.
让操作系统在一些更便宜的存储设备上为你处理这个。
So there's a paper from 15 years old now, from Jim Gray,
有一篇来自 15 年前的论文，来自 Jim Gray ，
which is one of the guys that the Turing Award for databases in the 90s,
他是 90 年代数据库图灵奖的获得者之一，
and he invented a lot of the stuff we're talking about this semester,
他发明了很多我们这学期讨论的东西，
he had a paper he wrote for at Microsoft a few years ago,
他有一篇几年前在微软写的论文，
that talks about whether, should you store large data in, in, in database system or not,
讨论了是否应该在数据库系统内存储大数据，
and I think for their recommendation,
我认为对于他们的建议，
they said anything larger than 200 kilobytes stored externally.
他们说的是任何大于 200 千字节的内容存储在外部。
Again, this is a while ago,
这是不久前的事，
I I I wouldn't recommend that anymore
我不再建议这样做了，
and actually we had the guy that invented SQLite,
实际上我们有一个发明了 SQLite 的人，
he came to cmu, gave a talk, five years ago,
他五年前来到 CMU ，做了一次演讲，
so, and he mentioned that,
他提到了，
in his experience, it's actually better to store things in, in SQLite,
根据他的经验，最好将东西存储在 SQLite 中，
like if you're running like a phone app,
如果你运行一个手机应用程序，
so if you have like your application has a bunch of thumbnails images,
如果您的应用程序有一堆缩略图图像，
you're better off storing that in the database system,
最好将其存储在数据库系统中，
because now when you, when you go retrieve them,
因为现在当你检索它们时，
your your application already has to handle to the database system open
你的应用程序已经必须处理数据库系统的打开，
as the file is already open,
文件已经打开，
so it's much faster to to go get those those thumbnails directly from the database system
所以直接从数据库系统读取这些缩略图要快的多，
versus having to do a bunch of fopens and freads to a bunch of files on disk.
比起对磁盘上的一堆文件进行一系列 fopen 和 fread 。
So I would say, I mean, this is pure conjecture,
所以我会说，我的意思是，这纯粹是猜测，
50 megs or less is probably okay,
50 兆或更少可能是可以的，
anything beyond that, you want to use external storage,
除此之外，你都希望使用外部存储，
and ORM, like Django and other other application frameworks,
像 Django 和其他应用程序框架这样的 ORM ，
they have mechanisms to handle that for you.
他们有为你处理这一问题的机制。
Okay?
好的？
So next class, next class,
所以下一节课，
we'll then continue on storage,
我们将继续讨论存储，
talk about storage models
谈论存储模型，
and then columns versus uh row storage
然后是列和行存储，
and this will be again explain to you why DuckDB is faster than SQLite
这将再次向你们解释为什么 DuckDB 比 SQLite 快，
and on that note, the DuckDB will sent me stickers,
在那个[笔记]上， DuckDB 会寄给我贴纸，
if you want one, come get one,
如果你想要一个，来拿一个，
I have pins too.
我也有别针。